[MUSIC]
Standford University. >> All right,
斯坦福大学
welcome then to lecture number eight. I think it's eight,
欢迎参加第八讲。好像是第八讲。
yes, of CS193P Spring of 2016. So today, we start off
是的，2016 春季 CS193P 课程。今天，我们将
by continuing that demo that we were doing last time.
继续完成上一次的 demo
Remember we had the demo, Cassini demo with the, scroll
今天用到之前 scroll view 写的 Cassini
view in there. And so I'm gonna make it more powerful,
让它功能更加强大.
we're gonna get multiple MVCs going in there.
我们将会用到多个 MVC 的结构.
We'll start doing some zooming in the scroll view.
会用到 scroll view 的缩放属性.
Depending on how the time goes I might actually show you some
如果有时间，我会通过实际案例来
things that couple of you have asked about on Piazza.
解答有些同学对 Piazza 项目的疑问.
Like, how to when I launch my calculator app can I have it
例如，在启动我的计算器 app 的时候，
not launch and show a blank graph, right,
因为没有启动图而显示空白的情况.
how can I have it launch and show the calculator for
怎样才能在在第一次启动计算器时，
the very first time, okay, those kinds of things.
显示启动页等，诸如此类的问题.
So we'll see how the time goes and
最后，我们会根据时间安排
decide on the fly whether to do that stuff.
来决定是否要解答这些.
Then we're gonna dive back into the slides.
让我们回到幻灯片上.
I'm gonna talk about multi-threading, okay?
我之后还会讲到多线程.
Very, very important thing in iOS is how to multithread
在 iOS 上，多线程的处理是非常非常重要的内容.
your execution. And then I'll go back to the demo, and
然后我们会回到 Cassini demo,
we'll multithread this Cassini thing we're working on, okay?
为它加上多线程支持.
And then time permitting at the end I'll go back to
在时间允许的情况下, 最后还会回到幻灯片
the slides and I'm gonna talk about text fields. And
讲一下 text field. 然后
then, next week we have table views, databases, etc. And
下周会讲 table view，database 等内容.
again, remember, no assignment going out today.
今天不会布置作业.
The assignment is gonna be a table view based thing, so
作业是基于 table view 的,
it will go out after Monday's lecture, all right? So,
所以我们会在下周一课程之后再布置, 没问题吧.
let's dive back into this Cassini demo. Okay,
那么, 让我们回到 Cassini demo.
we'll start off just exactly where we left off before. So
接着上一次的内容继续完善.
we'll go to Xcode here. So I'm just gonna open Cassini,
启动 Xcode, 打开 Cassini
here it is. I'm just gonna run it real quick just
我先来带大家快速过一遍
to remind you where we were for those with short memories.
回忆下之前的内容.
Even though it's only two days ago. All right,
虽然是两天前才讲的.
here it is. So we've got, our image view, right?
好的, 我们有一个 image view.
We have an ImageView and it's inside a UIScrollView, and so
这个 ImageView 嵌套在 UIScrollView 中,
we're able to scroll around, okay, just by panning with our
所以我们可以进行滚动, 用手指滑动就行
finger. My mouse is like a finger there, so
这光标就是手指
I'm just panning around, and that's all we can do, okay?
目前就只能随意滑动
But we've created this nice UI, or
但是我们这个漂亮的界面
this nice ImageViewController, which is an MVC that lets you
或者说, 漂亮的 ImageViewController 所用的 MVC 模式,
take any image and put it on screen inside the scroll view,
能任意将图片加入到 scroll view 中, 并显示出来
that's kind of a nice reusable, reusable MVC, right?
有很好的重用性, 重用 MVC, 对吧
So now we're going to make this a multi-MVC app, okay,
接下来, 我们会做一个多 MVC 的 app
and I'm gonna reuse this ImageViewController
重用的 ImageViewController
as one of the MVCs. So let's go right to our storyboard,
也是其中之一. 让我们打开 storyboard.
see what this is gonna look like.
来看看里面都有什么内容
This is where the Cassini part of this whole thing is gonna
Cassini 所展示的内容都从这里得到.
come in. All right, I'm gonna create a new View Controller,
现在, 我准备创建一个新的 View Controller
just gonna drag it out right here. Again,
将它拖到这里就可以了
I'm gonna go fairly quickly, cuz I've done this all before,
之前我们已经做过了, 所以这一步操作有点快
so this is almost like a review, for you here.
更像是在帮大家复习
So, I have this controller.
好, controller 创建好了
It needs to have a custom subclass of UIViewController
因为需要自定义 UIViewController
so I'm going to create such a thing. Go here to New File,
所以要做接下来的这些操作. 创建一个新文件
it's iOS source, it's a Cocoa Touch Class. Cuz it's
选择 iOS source, Cocoa Touch Class, 因为
a subclass of an iOS class, which is a UIViewController in
要子类化的类属于 iOS, 这里是 UIViewController
this case. I'm going to call this CassiniViewController,
类名就叫 CassiniViewController 吧
cuz it's gonna let us look at some Cassini images.
这个类会展示更多 Cassini 的图片
That's what our app is gonna do. But just in the same place
也是这个 app 的需求. 存放路径和之前一样
as always here is our CassiniViewController,
CassiniViewController 创建好了
I'm gonna remove the view controller lifecycle methods
暂时先删除模板给出的 view controller
that it gives me right here just for now anyway.
生命周期方法
And I'm actually gonna uncomment this prepareForSegue
然后打开 prepareForSegue 的注释
because my CassiniViewController is
因为 CassiniViewController 会
definitely going to be doing, some segueing.
用到这个方法, 一些 segue
So let's now go back to our storyboard,
现在让我们回到 storyboard
now that we have this ImageViewController class, and
我们已经有了 ImageViewController
I'm gonna change the class of this controller right here
再通过 identity inspector, 将这个
with the identity inspector, to be a CassiniViewController,
controller 改为 CassiniViewController
okay. Everybody got that? I'm going to put this whole
好的, 都能跟上吧? 接下来, 我会将整个
MVC structure into that split view with navigation that's
MVC 结构装到 split view 中
over in there, the thing that will work in both iPad and
这样就能同时用 iPad 和
iPhone, exact same thing we did for,
iPhone 上, 这种处理方式我们在
the emotions view controller. So, let's do that.
emotions view controller 上也做过. 下面来实现吧.
I'm going to start by dragging out the split view controller,
接下来需要拖一个 split view controller
I'm gonna zoom way out here.
先缩小画板
Let's go get a Split View Controller, here it is. I'll
然后找到 Split View Controller
drag it out. I'll get rid of these extra things that came
拖拽出来. 删掉除了
along here with the Split View Controller because I already
Split View Controller 的其他内容, 因为我们已经
have my master and detail right here. The Cassini's
有自己的 master 和 detail 了. Cassini 是
gonna be my master and this ImageViewController's gonna be
master, ImageViewController 是 detail.
my detail right there. So I'm just gonna Control drag, hook
按住 Control 并拖拽到 master
up my master. And a Control drag, hook up my detail.
然后按住 Control 并拖拽到 detail
I'm also gonna take my little entry arrow and make it so
接下来, 将入口箭头移动到
that it enters on the Split View Controller. Right,
Split View Controller
instead of entering on my Image View Controller,
Image View Controller 不再是入口
obviously. And, I want this to work on both iPhone and iPad,
我想要在 iPhone 和 iPad 上使用
so I'm gonna take my master and put it embedded inside
所以, 我准备将 master 嵌入到
of a navigation controller, okay? And maybe I can even go
navigation controller 中, 然后我能在这
in here and put a nice title here, right here. Cassini,
给它加上 title. Cassini.
okay? All right now, what is this UI going to do?
跟上了吗? 最终, 这个界面到底有什么作用?
What's it going to look like? How's it gonna function?
长什么样呢? 怎样触发一些功能?
Well, I'm just gonna have three buttons here.
好的, 我会在这里放 3 个按钮
Similar to how I had in emotions view controller.
和之前的 emotions view controller 很像
In a demo I can only do, I can't do a nice complicated
在 demo 中也只能这样了, 不能像计算器
MVC like a calculator and then another complicated one like
一样有复杂的 MVC 结构, 也不能像
a graph view. I have to do a simple one. So I'm gonna do
graph view 那样复杂. 只能做个简单的界面了. 所以我也只好
a simple one here. Where I'm gonna put three buttons and
这样了. 之所以我要放三个按钮,
those three buttons are just going to cause three different
是因为要展示三张
images from NASA, okay, about Cassini which is a little
NASA 的图片. 至于 Cassini, 它是被
thing sent out into space to take pictures. I'm gonna put
发送到太空来拍摄图片的. 我会把
those three buttons here and then were just gonna segue,
三个按钮放到这, 然后我们处理 segue,
as we know how to do, down to here,
大家应该知道怎么做. 将 ImageViewController
which is gonna be our ImageViewController,
放到下面来
all right. So the Image View Controller's just gonna show
Image View Controller 会用来显示图片
the image, and we already know that the Image View Controller
我们已经知道展示图片的 Image View Controller 是一个
is a nice, little, reasonable MVC that shows an image.
优雅的, 小巧的, 合理的 MVC 结构.
So it's perfect, exactly what I want. So
如此完美, 正是我们想要的
I'm gonna go down here and get the buttons. So it's this
向下滚动, 找到按钮.
button right here. Let's go ahead and make it bigger,
将按钮放在这. 继续, 把它放大点,
I'll say 40 point would be a pretty good size here.
设置为 40 点看起来比较好
And, make three of them, copy, paste so
然后创建三个这样按钮, 复制, 粘贴
I get that. Okay, one of them is gonna be called Earth,
好了, 一个叫做 Earth
another one is gonna be called Cassini.
一个叫做 Cassini.
And another one is gonna be called Saturn, okay?
剩下的一个叫 Saturn, 好了吗?
And then I'm just gonna take these three things.
然后, 将这三个按钮
Of course it put them in a stack view.
放到 stack view 中
Okay, we'll go ahead and have the stack view be fill.
ok, 将 stack view 对齐方式设置为 fill.
And we'll also do again fill equally.
然后将分布设置为 fill equally.
It doesn't really matter because they're all identical,
这些都无关紧要, 它们都是相同的
they're all buttons. We'll put a little spacing in there,
都是按钮. 然后给它们加一些间隙
maybe. 20 points something like that. Then I'm gonna drag
20 点之类的. 接下来将它拖到
this into the middle use my blue lines right there so that
视图中间, 有蓝色对齐线这里
I can go here and say Reset to suggested constraints.
点击这里, 选择 Reset to suggested constraints (重置为建议约束).
And then I'm gonna go over to my size inspector and
接着看到 size inspector
double check that it did the kind of constraints I want.
再次确认约束是否正确添加
Which that looks good to me it's gonna align these things
看来这些约束能正确将
in the center, okay? So, here's our UI right here.
视图居中, 好了吗? 这就是我们的 UI 了.
Now, all we need to do is have these three things segue down
现在, 就只需要将这三个按钮的事件和下面
to here to fill these images. Now, I'll show you where these
这个关联, 来显示图片了. 之后, 我会展示这些
images come from in a minute here, but let's just create
图片从哪来, 现在先来创建 segue.
the segue. Now, I'm gonna do something a little different
这次我们处理 segue 的方式和之前不一样.
with this segue. In our last one I, each segue had
之前, 每个 segue 都有
its own identifier that was different, and
自己的 identifier, 每一个都不同
it was the identifier that let us know which emotion to
这些 identifier 使我们知道应该
show in the emotions one. Here I'm gonna have them all have
显示哪个表情. 这一次, 它们只有
the same identifier, and I'm gonna use the title of
一个相同的 identifier, 我将使用按钮的 title
the button to decide which image, okay? So it's kind of
来决定显示的图片. 所以,
a cross between what we did in the calculator and
这和我们之前做计算器,
what we did in emotions, all right? So, let's go ahead and
做表情的处理不一样.
create these things. So, I'm gonna, Control drag, okay,
下面我们来创建 segue 吧. 按钮 Contorl 并拖拽,
from Saturn down to here. This is in a split view, right,
从 Saturn 到这里. 他们都在 split view 中.
so I'm gonna do Show Detail, right?
选择 Show Detail.
That's the kind of segue I want, not show. The same thing
这才是我想要的 segue, 而不是 Show.
with Cassini right here, Show Detail. And then up here to
Cassini 也是同样, ShowDetail. 接着是
Earth, Show Detail. Whoops, not Present Modally, undo,
Earch, Show Detail. 噢, 不是 Present Modally, 撤销,
let's try that again. Show Detail. Okay, so
重新来一次, Show Detail.
we've got these three things here. Let's go ahead and
这三个就关联好了. 然后来检查下.
inspect them. I'm gonna put an identifier on them but
我准备给它们设置 identifier, 但
they're all gonna have the same identifier.
它们的 identifier 都相同.
And what that means is when prepareForSegue gets called,
那么, 这在调用 prepareForSegue 时意味着什么呢
it's gonna be called, and the same thing is gonna happen for
调用时, 他们所触发的事件都是相同的.
each one. Again I'm gonna look at the sender in
不过, 可以通过
prepareForSegue to know which button,
prepareForSegue 的 sender 来区别按钮,
but we're gonna use the same code. So I'm gonna call this
但是它们的代码是共用的. 所以, 就命名为
Show Image, cuz that's what it does, okay, when you click On
Show Image 吧, 见名知意.
here to segue, it segues to this image view controller and
点击 Segue, 跳转到 image view controller
shows an image. Okay, so let's make sure all three of
显示图片. 确保三个按钮都
them are doing that. Okay, so everybody cool with this?
设置好. 好了, 大家对这一步有疑问吗?
This is all just review, I haven't done anything new, yet
以上是对之前的回顾，还没添加新的知识点
here. K, now of course we know if we want these
如果想要这些 segue 生效
little segues here to work, we need to prepare them, so
还需要准备 segue
let's go back to our Cassini View Controller right here and
接下来回到 Cassini View Controller，
do our prepare for segue. I'm gonna show you something
准备 segue. 接下来我会演示如何
that's kind of nice to do from a clean coding mechanism,
在用纯代码来实现
which is I like to create a private struct here to
我比较喜欢创建一个私有 struct
store my constants that are strings in the storyboard.
来存放 storyboard 中 string 类型的常量
So I usually call this thing storyboard okay? And then I
所以命名为 storyboard
just put these static lets inside. So the ShowImageSegue
然后将这些静态常量放到 struct 中. ShowImageSegue
= "Show Image". So that this string, and basically any
= "Show Image". 就是这样. 在
string that I put anywhere in my story board, like in these,
storyboard 中的其他 string 也都和这个类似，
when I inspect these things down here like this string.
比如看到的这个下面这个 string
Okay? That's all collected here into this nice struct.
将这些都添加到 struct 中
Okay? So
到此，
we already know that this is what we do to do constants,
我们已经知道怎样处理这些常量了
okay? I'm just calling this group of constants storyboard.
我暂且把这个集合称为 storyboard 常量集吧
They're my storyboard constants, all right?
这就是我的 storyboard 常量集了
All right, so let's do prepare for segue right here.
然后在这里准备 segue
What do we need to do in prepare for segue?
我们需要在 prepareForsSegue 中做哪些处理？
Well first of all, we probably want to make sure that this is
首先，我们要确保 segue 是
the show image segue, so I'm going to say if the segue's
show image segue，所以先进行判断
identifier = the storyboard.ShowImageSegue.
segue 的 identifier 是否等于 Storyboard.ShowImageSegue
Okay? Then we know this is what we're preparing for.
这一步是保证我们处理的是正确的 segue
And remember,
记住，在一个复杂的 app 中，可能会有很多不同的
of segues, like we have in emotions actually, with
segue，就像我们有不同的情绪一样，它们有
different identifiers going off. So that's why we almost
不同的标识. 所以我们
always check the identifier first just to make sure
通常使用 identifier 来确保
that we are doing the right thing, and
处理方式是对的
usually we'll try and spell identifier properly. Okay.
当然，还需要正确的拼写 identifier
So now, we know this is the right segue. We need to get
现在，我们知道这里就是想要的 segue 了. 还需要
the MVC that we're segueing to so we can prepare it.
有一个 MVC 结构来准备 segue
So we know that's supposed to be an Image View Controller so
假设需要的是 Image View Controller
I'm going to say if I can let IVC, short for
所以定义一个叫做 ivc 的常量
Image View Controller,
ImageViewController 的简写
equal the segue's destination view controller as
等于 segue 的 destinationViewController
an image view controller. Okay.
转换为 ImageViewController
So if I, I don't even need the parentheses there, sorry. So
这里不需要大括号，不好意思
if I can get that destination view controller as an image
如果能正确将 destinationViewController 转为
view controller then now I'm ready to prepare this thing.
ImageViewController，那么就可以开始做一些准备了
So, how do I need to prepare it? Well,
怎样去准备呢？
it depends on which button Is doing this show image, okay.
这要取决于哪个按钮触发显示图片事件
So, I'm actually gonna look back at the button. Now,
所以，回头看看这些按钮
here's the button. Remember it prepares for segue.
这个参数就是按钮，并且是谁触发的 segue，
The sender is the button or the line in a table or
那这个 sender 就是谁，可能是按钮或者 table 的某一行
something like that that caused it to happen.
或者其他触发事件的对象
So, I need to convert this into a button. So
所以，我需要将它强转为 button
I could actually do this like this. I could say, if I can
我可以这样做，如果 sender
let the sending button equal the sender as a UI button,
是 UIButton，并解包给 sendingButton 不为空
then I can go forward here and say let's let the image name,
那么就可以定义一个 imageName
that's the name of the image we wanna show,
代表我们想要显示的图片名称
equal the sending button's current title. Oops,
并将 sendingButton 的当前图片，哦，不
not current image, current title. All right, so
当前标题.
this'll be one way to do this,
这是一种处理方式
okay, but kind of a cool way here is, this is this, right?
但是还有一种更好的方法，看这个和这个
So what if I took this, cut and
如果我将这个
put it in here like that. Okay, so
剪切到这里
I don't need this except for this is If, let. So, if I put
那就不再需要这个 if let 了，但如果
this in here, this is going to be an optional. I can't send
将它放到这里，那这就会是个可选值，不能从可选值
current title to an optional. So, how can I deal with that?
中直接访问 currentTitle 属性. 该怎么办呢？
Let's use optional chaining. Okay? So it's perfectly legal
让我们试试可选链. 在表达式返回可选值的时候
to use the optional chaining stuff on the end of some,
使用可选链来操作
some other expression that returns a possible optional.
是完全合法的
And remember, if this is nil right here,
如果这里是 nil
then this whole thing's just gonna be ignored.
那么之后的都会被忽略
That's what the question mark means, it means if it's nil,
这个问号就是表示可能为 nil
nil then just return nil and ignore it.
遇到 nil 会返回 nil，然后忽略掉
That means imageName is gonna be returned to nil. Okay.
也就是说 imageName 可能为 nil
See how I did that? This cleans up our code a little
接下来做什么呢？先把代码
bit, to do that. Less if then, if thens and
整理一下. 减少分支语句
all that, business around there. Okay? Now I'm going
接下来，要根据
to go get the image that goes with this button's title.
按钮的 title 来获取图片
Now let me show you how we're gonna do that.
让我来演示一下
This DemoURL class, remember the one that had that little
这个 DemoURL 类，有一个 Stanford 的 URL
Stanford URL in there? Well it also had these NASA URLs,
还有 NASA 的 URL
one for Cassini, one for Earth, and one for Saturn.
里面包含 Cassini，Earth 和 Saturn
Those are the three buttons we have. And
对应着我们的三个按钮
I have a little function right here that just gets the name
这还有个简单的方法，接收图片名称
of the image and looks it up in that dictionary right here,
然后在字典中查找
okay, and returns it. So this a little function called
并返回，所以这个方法叫
NASA Image Named. So let's use this NASA Image Named.
NASAImageNamed. 来调用下这个方法
I'm just gonna say right here that the IVC's image URL
在这里写 ivc 的 imageURL
equals the NASAImageNamed this imageName. Okay?
等于 NASAImageNamed 的这个 imageNames
This thing I got right here. >> [COUGH]
就这样
>> All right.
能跟上吗
And then, oops, sorry, this has gotta be DemoURL.,
接下来，哦，不好意思，要加上 DemoURL.
because it's over here in this DemoURL.
因为这个方法在 DemoURL 中
Notice this is a static function, right?
注意这是个静态方法
NASAImageNamed is static function.
NASAImageNamed 是个静态方法
So, we send it to the class DemoURL, that's why I had to
所以应该用 DemoURL 类来调用，所以
put DemoURL here. Okay, just kind of a utility function for
应该加上 DemoURL. 这只是 DemoURL 中
that little DemoURL class. And while we're at it,
的一个工具方法而已. 接下来，
you know what, let's set the title of that MVC to be that
将 MVC 结构的 title 设置为
image name as well. So that way we'll Earth or Cassini or
图片名字吧. 这样 MVC 的 title 会是 Earth 或 Cassini
whatever as the title of that MVC. Okay so this make sense?
或者其他的名字. 这就是这段代码的作用
Everybody okay now? Let's go ahead and run this and
都能跟上吗？运行程序
see if this is working. Here we go.
看看效果
Okay, there we go. So here's Cassini right here, and
运行起来了，这是 Cassini，
if I click Earth, okay, whoa. So it worked. I clicked Earth
如果我点击 Earth，有点击效果. 点击了 Earth
but nothing's happening in my app. Wait, no there,
但是 app 却没做出响应. 等下，不对啊
it's showing Stanford. Why is is showing Stanford here?
这展示的是斯坦福，为什么会这样？
Well, that's because our nice reusable image view controller
那是因为我们重用的 ImageViewController
we have over here, it's view did load smashes Stanford on
的 viewDidLoad 方法中，将斯坦福盖在了
top of everything. So, that we only put that in there as
所有视图的顶部. 这只是之前的 demo
a demo. Right, so I'm taking that out, sorry about that.
把它提出来，不好意思
Makes everyone see what happened there. So
现在来看看都发生了什么
now let's go back here. It won't be slamming a Stanford
重新运行一次，这下我们的重用 ImageViewController
in there in our reusable image view controller. Okay? So
应该不会被斯坦福盖住了
now we'll go back to Cassini. We'll pick Earth this time.
回到 Cassini 界面，选择 Earth
Again it seems like it's kinda stuck. I can't click on any of
又卡住了. 所有按钮都
these buttons. I can't, actually I can't do anything.
无法点击. 点不了，什么都做不了
There it is. Okay. So that must have been a really big
进来了，真是一张大图
image. It took a very long time to load and here it is.
需要这么长的时间加载，终于显示出来了
It doesn't really look like Earth, but
看起来不怎么像是地球，
pictures of people on Earth, hm. That's interesting.,
倒像是地球上的人，有意思.
Let's try one of these others. Let's try Cassini here. Okay,
再试试别的，试试 Cassini
what happening? This is, basically, just blank.
怎么回事，怎么只有一个白板
What's going on here? How about Saturn? Again,
怎么回事？再试试 Saturn 呢？又来了
taking a really long time, you can see why we're gonna talk
又要等很久，这就是为什么之后我们要讲
about multi-threading a little later. Okay, and here it is,
多线程. 好，进来了
okay that's not good either. All right, so
看起来也不怎么像. 好吧，
we gotta start here. We know the Cassini's not working.
刚才发现 Cassini 没能正常显示
It comes up blank. So why might Cassini not be working.
看到一片空白，为什么会这样
Let's go back here and check for example to make sure that
回到这里，检查下 segue 有没有什么问题
our segue is good. Okay, the Earth's segue. Here's
这是 Earth 的 segue，这是
the Cassini segue. Let';s go look at its identifier.
Cassini 的 segue. 来检查下它的 identifier
Look at that. This Cassini identifier, no identifier.
看到没，Cassini 的 identifier 是空的
So let's put show image in here. Okay?
设置为 Show Image
So when you have a segue and it doesn't seem to be working,
所以，如果你有一个segue，但是没能正常响应
like it segues to the new MVC but
比如想推出一个新的 MVC，但是
the prepared doesn't happen, often you want to go back and
prepare 中的代码没有运行，通常需要回头
look at your identifier, make sure it's set properly or
检查下 identifier，确保它正确的
set in there. Okay, so now, if we go back here.
赋了值. 现在重新运行
All right, we have Cassini here. Let's click on it.
找到 Cassini 并点击
Again, it's loading. That one must be a smaller image.
再次等待加载，这图片应该不大
It loaded pretty quick. And here it is.
加载起来很快，显示出来了
It looks like it's just a bunch of outer space. Okay, so
看起来就只是外太空而已
we've got a problem here,
现在有一个问题
which is that these images that I loaded are huge. That's
当我们加载一些大图的时候
created two problems for us. One, our app get's blocked.
有两个问题摆在了面前. 一个是 app 被卡死了
See I can't click on anything else. I can't even rotate or
任何东西都没办法点击. 连旋转都不行
anything here. My app is just completely stuck.
app 完完全全卡住
You never want your app in that circumstance.
你肯定不想你的 app 出现这样的情况
Never should your app be stuck like that. Users will just,
你们的 app 绝不能出现这样的情况. 用户发现，
basically, double click on the home button and
就会双击 home 键
kill your app and never run it again.
然后杀死进程，再也不会用了
They'll think your app is totally hosed. And it is,
他们会觉得你的 app 太烂了，这就是
if it behaves that way, okay, so we really need to fix that.
界面卡死的后果，所以我们需要修复下
The other thing is, this image is so
另外一个问题就是，图片太大
huge that we can't really see it. So we'd like to be able to
无法直观的展示. 所以我们要添加
zoom in on it, right. So let's go ahead and
缩放功能. 先来处理
do the zooming, okay? How do we do the zooming in our,
缩放吧. 怎么在 ImageViewController 中
back here in our image view controller, right?
做缩放呢？
So our image view controller has this scroll view,
ImageViewController 有一个 scrollView
right? That we dragged into the storyboard. It's got this
我们拖到 storyboard 中的. 并将 imageView 添加
image view as the subview of the scroll view. Okay, and
到了 scrollView 上
we set our content size, so it's working nicely. And
我们还设置了 contentSize，看起来非常棒
we know from the slides last time that
从之前的幻灯片我们知道了
to make zooming work. Okay, we need to set some other things.
缩放的原理. 那这里还需要处理一些东西
What are some of the things we need to do? Well,
需要怎么做呢？
the most important thing is we need to set ourselves
最重要的一点，就是要将我们自己设置为
as the scrollView's delegate. Okay, so
scrollView 的 delegate.
this is the first time you're seeing delegation demoed here.
这是我们在 demo 中第一次用到 delegate
And the way we do that,
我的做法是
I'd probably do it here in my scrollView didSet here, right?
在 scrollView 的 didSet 方法中来设置
The didSet for my scrollView. Probably just say that Mr.
这就是 scrollView 的 didSet 方法. 这样说，
scrollView, please set your delegate to be self. In other
亲爱的 scrollView，让我成为你的代理吧！换句话说，
words, send me any questions you have about how to operate.
就是把你的问题抛给我来处理吧
Now when I put that in there I have a error,
照我这样设置出现了一个错误
anyone guess what this error is? Okay,
有谁知道这是什么错误吗？
it's going to say that these types, this and
错误是说，他们的类型，这个和
this do not match. Okay, and why is that? The type of this
这个不匹配. 为什么呢？这个的类型是...
is, well the type of this, not showing, but the type of this
好吧，看不到，但是这个的类型是
is UI scrollView delegate. Which is a protocol, okay.
UIScrollViewDelegate. 是个协议
The type of this is UI or image view controller.
这个类型是 UI...哦，是ImageViewController
That's its type. Those don't match. Okay, so
这就是它们的类型，并不匹配. 难怪
that's why this says cannot assign value of type image
报错说不能将 ImageViewController
view controller to UI scroll view delegate, optional.
赋值给可选的 UIScrollViewDelegate
Okay, so we need to say that this image view controller is
所以，我们要先让 ImageViewController 遵循
a UI scroll view delegate. And we do that by just putting
UIScrollViewDelegate. 需要做的是，将 UIScrollViewDelegate 声明在
that right after our super class there, a little comma,
父类的右边，逗号分隔
UIScrollViewDelegate, and that says we are scroll view
这表明我们就是 scrollView
delegate, and all of a sudden this works.
的代理，这样就没问题了
Now UIScrollViewDelegate has no methods or
UIScrollViewDelegate 没有方法或
vars in there that are not optional. In other words
变量是不可选的，换句话说，
they're all optional, so we've successfully implemented so
它们都是可选的，所以，遵循以后
the compiler's not complaining. Okay,
编译器并没有报错
cuz none of them are required. But, we still wanna implement
因为没有必须实现的方法. 不过我们还是需要实现
one, that zooming one, which is called
其中一个方法，缩放的那个，叫做
viewForZoomingInScrollView. Now, one
viewForZoomingInScrollView. 在你
thing that's cool is once you say that you're a ScrollView
成为 ScrollView 的代理之后，
delegate, look what happens when I start typing view
在最新的 Xcode 键入字母时
in Xcode. It knows I'm a ScrollView delegate, so
它就知道你已经是 ScrollView 的代理了，所以
the very first thing it offers me is viewForScroll,
提供的首个联想方法就是 viewForScroll
ScrollingInScrollView. For
ZoomingInScrollView（白胡子口误了）
zooming in scrollView.、 Right? So that's kind of cool. And
用做 scrollView 的缩放. 这真的非常棒
what view, which of the scrollView subviews do we want
那个视图？我们想让 scrollView 的哪个子视图
to zoom in on? Well, of course, the image view. This
做缩放？当然是 imageView. 这是
is our image view right here that we store our image in.
我们的 imageView，里面存储了相应图片
That's of course the thing we want
很明显我们是想
to have its transform modified when we pinch in there. Okay?
在手指捏合的时候，对图片做对应的缩放
Now you might think okay, that's good.
你可能会想，那已经完成了，
Got it all ready to go. Let's go start zooming, and
可以运行了. 让我来看看缩放效果吧
we'll go over here. Let's get Cassini, kinda small.
到这个界面，打开 Cassini，一张小图
Let's start zooming. Now how do I zoom? It's with Pinch, so
试试缩放. 怎么进行缩放呢？需要捏合手势，所以
I'm gonna hold down the Option key right here and
按住 Option 键，然后
start pinching. And it's not working.
进行捏合. 但并没有效果
It's not doing anything. Okay, I can still scroll but
完全没有效果. 依然可以滚动，但是
I can't zoom in. Anyone know why? Say
不能缩放. 有人知道为什么吗？大点声.
it louder. I think I might have heard it back there.
我刚才好像听到那有人回答.
Yeah, this right now, our scrollView by default,
是的，没错，现在 scrollView 的默认值是
it's maximum zoom and its minimum zoom is 1.0.
放大倍数和缩小倍数都是 1.0
So it is zooming to the maximum,
所以我们放大
minimum extent we allow which is none, 1.0. So
和缩小的效果根本看不出来，都是 1.0，所以
we need to set the maximum and minimum scrolling factor or
我们需要给 scrollView 的范围因子，或叫做给
zooming factor on this scrollView. So let's do that.
缩放因子赋值. 回到代码.
Let's do that also right here when we're setting our
在这里进行设置，在
scrollView from our storyboard. So
scrollView 在 storyboard 中被赋值时调用的方法
we just say that the scrollView's minimum zoom
键入 scrollView 的 minimumZoomScale
scale. I'm gonna have this minimum zoom scale.
来设置最小缩放因子
What did I think that worked well here? 0.03.
设成多少效果比较好呢？0.03 吧
So we're gonna zoom- allowed to zoom way out.
我们可以进行缩放
So it will make the image really small, okay?
图片会缩小到很小
Three one-hundredths of it's size.
是原图的百分之三
3% of its size. And then the maximum,
也就是 3% 的大小，接下来设置最大因子
it is perfectly fine for us to say the maximum is 1.0.
这个值设为 1.0 就好了
Maybe we never want the thing to be zoomed out any bigger
可能我们永远不会将该图片放大
than it already is, especially there are huge images already.
毕竟它已经是一张很大的图片了
So we can set the maximum to zoom scale. We don't even need
其实我们完全可以不用设置放大因子，这条
to put this. Cuz by default, it's 1.0. But we'll put it
语句可以不用谢，因为默认值就是 1.0. 这里就不删了，
in here just to kinda be very clear about what we're doing.
看着更清晰一点
All right, so now lets try it. All right,
再来看看效果
so lets go get Cassini right here. All right, here it is.
点击 Cassini，然后
Lets zoom in on it, right. I'm pinching. Yeah, look at that,
进行缩放，捏合一下，看到了吧
it's zooming. And sure enough, look,
缩小了. 效果很好
there's Cassini. Taking a little trip by Saturn, okay,
这是 Cassini，在围着 Saturn 兜风
let's zip it around here so we can see a little better. Okay,
旋转一下屏幕，就能看到更多内容
how about some of these other images, go look at the Earth,
来看看其他图片呢，看看 Earch
didn't look like much like Earth. Now if we zoom,
之前看着并不像 Earth. 这次缩小试试
we'll see something here. All right, so here it is,
说不定能看到更多东西. 好了，加载出来了
scrolling around, I'm gonna pinch, pinch some more.
滚动看看，然后捏合，再缩小点
Look at this Earth, okay? Same thing with Saturn.
啊哈，这就是 Earch. 在看看 Saturn 呢
Okay, everyone see what we do with the zooming?
每个人都知道怎么实现缩放了吗？
Zooming quite simple
实现起来真的很简单
in terms of the code you have to write, but
就那么几句代码
you have to understand that delegation piece for
这全都要靠 delegate
it to really, to make it work. And you'll see Saturn,
那才是真谛. 来看看 Saturn
there's Saturn. Okay? Now let's try this on iPad,
这是 Saturn. 没问题，运行在 iPad 上试试，
okay? Let's see what it looks like here.
看看显示效果
All right, so here is our master and
这是 master
our detail right here. So if I click on Cassini,
这是 detail，点击 Cassini，
hopefully Cassini will eventually really slow,
加载起来确实很慢
appear right here. Okay? And we can zoom in here, okay?
显示出来了，缩放试试呢
Now, what would be really cool here is if we could have
如果在这里能有个标题
a title up here that said this was Cassini,
告诉我们这是 Cassini，
or Earth, or Saturn, right? So remember
还是是 Earth，是 Saturn，就更好了
the tricky way we did that, is we went to our storyboard, and
其实有一个很取巧的方式，打开 storyboard
we just put this one down here. Also in the scrollView.
将下面的这个包含 scrollView 的控制器
So we said embed in navigation control.
加上 navigation
Or not in a scrollView, in a navigation controller. So
或者嵌入到 navigation controller 中
I embed it in there, so that now I have a title. Right? And
嵌入之后，就可以设置标题了
we know that if we can go and
如果现在运行
run this, it's not going to work, right? Because these
不会有任何效果，因为
segues are segueing now to a navigation controller. And
现在这个 segue 是 navigation controller 了.
so our prepare is not gonna work,
所以 prepare 方法不会有效
cuz this line of code is going to fail. Right,
这句代码代码判断失败了
because the destination view controller is now a navigation
现在这个 destinationViewController 是 navigationController
controller. Of course,
显然，
a navigation controller is not an image view controller.
navigationController 不是 imageViewController
This is the exact same problem we had before. So
这种问题我们之前遇到过
I'm gonna show you now how to use that extensions mechanism
下面我将演示如何使用 extension 来
to fix this. So I'm gonna create an extension. This is
解决这个问题. 先创建一个 extension.
exactly what I did in the slides of UIViewController.
这是给 UIViewController 的 extension.
Okay, and in this extension, like to scroll up a little so
好的，在 extension 中，好像往下滚动一点
you can see it better. Okay, inside this extension,
更方便你们看. 好的，在这个 extension 中，
I'm gonna add the var contentViewController.
我准备添加一个 contentViewController 变量.
Which is a UIViewController, okay?
类型是 UIViewController
I'm adding this var to the class UIViewController.
这是给 UIViewController 添加的变量
So, all UIViewControllers will now respond to this property
所以所有的 UIViewController 都有一个叫做
contentViewController. Okay? It's gonna be get only.
contentViewController 的属性了. 将它声明为只读属性.
It's gonna get it. And what I'm gonna put in here is
直接就能获取值. 这里的代码和
basically that same code I had in prepareforSegue,
motion view controller 中的 prepareforSegue 方法
in a motionview controller. I'm gonna say,
代码相同，这样写，
if I can let navcon = self as a UINavigationController,
if let navcon = self as? UINavigationController，
so in otherwords, if I am a navigation controller,
意思是，如果 self 是 UINaviagtionController，
then return navcon.visibleViewController.
就返回 navcon.visibleViewController.
Okay? The only problem with this is this is
这里唯一的问题就是
an optional view controller, because the navigation
这个 view controller 是可选值，因为 navigation
controller might not have anything showing. Okay, so
controller 可能不会展示任何信息，所以
I need to return something because contentViewController
这里必须要返回一个确切的值，因为 contentViewController
does not return an optional So I'm gonna use this
不是一个可选类型. 所以我准备用 ?? 将默认值
defaulting to say if I have a NavigationController and
设置为 self，如果有 NavigationController
it has no visible ViewController, just return
但是 visibleViewController 为空的话，就返回
self, which is to say the NavigationController itself,
self，也就是 NavigationController
okay? Otherwise, we can just return self. So if it's not
其他情况，就返回 self. 即如果不是
a NavigationController, then the content is myself.
NavigationController，就返回 self 作为 content
Everyone understand that code right there? Okay? Good.
大家对这段代码有疑问吗？没有？好的.
So, now that we have this, we can just use that method right
有了这个以后，我们在这里直接调方法就可以了.
here. Okay? Instead of asking if the destination can view
这里还要把之前判断的 destination view
controller is an image view controller, I'm gonna ask if
controller 是 imageViewController 改为判断
the destination controller's content view controller, and
destination controller 的 content view controller 是否是
I can escape complete, cuz now that's a method on U, I,
imageViewController. 现在这个方法，哦，这个
this is a UI view controller. This is a method on UI view
就是 UIViewController 了，这个方法就是 UIViewController 的
controller. I'm just gonna ask if the content view controller
只需要判断 content view controller 是否
is an image view controller. Okay? So now we should be able
是 image view controller 就行了. 现在在 iPad 上跑起来
to run an iPad and get some nice titles. All right.
应该就可以看到标题了.
Cassini again. We've got the navigation controller up here.
依然打开 Cassini，能看到这里有个 navigation controller
There's Cassini. Sure enough, there's the title, right.
这是 Cassini，没问题，这是标题
We set the title right here. Ivc.title = imageName, okay?
我们在这里加上了标题，ivc.title = imageName
And of course, we can zoom around, okay?
当然，我们还可以进行缩放
All right, any questions about that before I go back to
讲到这里，大家有什么问题吗？
the slides? All right. Let's hit the slides here.
好的，再回到讲义.
Okay, so now we're gonna talk about multithreading, so
接下来，我会讲讲多线程
we can fix that problem where our Cassini app,
这样就能修复 Cassini app 中，当我们加载大图时
when we click on the big image, it just froze. Okay.
导致的界面卡死问题了.
When you build an app, never have it freeze like that ever.
当你做一款 app 时，千万不要出现界面卡死的情况
In fact, if it freezes like that, probably you won't get
事实上，出现界面卡死的情况，
through the app store approval process. Okay. So the only
还会影响你上架 app store. 解决界面卡死的
way to stop it from freezing is to use multithreading.
唯一方式，就是使用多线程.
Okay. So, multithreading just means we're going to
多线程意味着我们会在
have different threads of execution,
不同的线程中执行任务
okay? Different places in, in our iPhone or
在，在 iPhone 或 iPad 的不同的地方
our iPad where code is running, okay?
执行代码
And these, these appear to run simultaneously, but
这些代码，几乎是同时运行的，
it'll even work on a single core processor, okay,
即使在单核处理器上，也没问题
not a multiprocessor. It works, then, by timesharing.
虽然不是多核处理，但是运用了分时操作手段
Okay. And so you got one thing running,
所以，一个事件在执行，
another thing running and it's kinda going back and
然后再切换到另一个事件，执行后又切回刚才的事件
forth. Letting them each run a little bit and maybe if one of
继续执行. 每个事件都能执行一段时间，如果某个事件
them's more important than the other, it gets run a lot and
在其中比较重要，那么就会停留得就一些，
the other one doesn't get to run so much. Okay? But
次要的事件就不会占用那么长事件.
that's basically what multithreading is all about.
这就是多线程最基础的部分.
So how many people have,
在做的有同学已经，
have done any multithreading programming of any kind? Okay,
已经做过多线程的项目了？好吧，
so some of you have, okay. About a little less than half
一部分同学，大概不到一半的人吧。
of you. Okay, good. So in iOS multithreading is about
谈到 iOS 上的多线程，其实都是
queues, okay? Queue meaning like, if you go to the movies
队列. 队列就像是...如果你在 England 去
maybe in England [LAUGH] they would say, well,
看电影，那么他们会说，
get in the queue, meaning the line to get into the movie,
排队去，意思是，排队依次进电影院.
okay? So same thing here, and it's the same thing as queue
这里的队列和计算机科学中队列
in the computer science sense, right? A queue is a thing,
的含义是一样的. 队列其实就是一个东西，
a bunch of things lined up to do something.
一个有先后顺序的东西.
All right. And these queues contained an iOS functions.
这些队列包含了 iOS 的方法.
Okay? Most of the time these functions are closures. Okay?
绝大多数方法都是闭包. 好吧？
That you've put in there. Okay? Blocks of code that you
然后加入到队列中. 就是闭包中的代码，
put in this queue. Okay? And then, the system simply runs
加入到队列中. 接着，系统会单独运行
along this queue, pulls the next thing off the queue and
这个队列，将队列中的任务取出，
starts it running in a separate thread, okay?
然后在独立的线程中运行.
And you can have multiple of these queues and the system is
你也可以有很多个队列，然后系统便会
pulling them off each one and running them un, in their
分别取出，然后...在各自的线程中
own threads, simple as that, you just got multithreading.
执行，就这么简单的用上了多线程.
Okay. Now there's a little bit of trickiness
那么现在有个问题，
here of what are these queues and
队列是什么，
how do you put things on the queues, but
怎么将任务加入到队列中，
that's the fundamental way these work. Now queues can
这属于队列运行原理. 队列可以是
either be serial, which means the function that's on the top
串行的，意思是只有当上一个任务执行完后，
of the queue gets pulled off, it runs to completion, and
新的队首元素才会出队
then the next one gets pulled off. That's serial queues. Or
接着执行. 这就是串行队列.
they can be concurrent, where the system pulls the top
队列也可以是并行的，意思是系统出队
one off the queue, starts it running in a thread. If it's
一个队首元素，就立即在一个线程中执行. 如果是这样，
got more thread resources, it takes the next one off,
就会占用更多的资源，下一个任务出队以后
starts it running in another thread while the first one's
就会在另一个线程中进行执行，此时，第一个出队的任务
still running, and
仍在执行，
it might keep pulling a whole bunch of them off. Okay, so
这种队列甚至可以直接将整个队列元素出队执行.
that's a concurrent queue.
这就是并行队列.
All right, so let's talk about the queues, how we get them,
接下来，再来看看队列的其他知识. 我们怎么获得队列，
what, what we call them, etc. The most important queue,
怎样调用它们，等等. 对重要的队列，
it's a serial queue called the main queue, okay?
就是一个称为主队列的串行队列.
The main queue is where all UI activity has to happen. And
主队列是刷新 UI 控件的队列.
this is super important for you to understand. That if you
大家一定要着重理解这个知识点. 如果你在
want to do anything where you call something a UI kit, okay,
做一些和 UIKit 相关的动作，比如
UI button, UI anything, all right,
UIButton，或其他 UI 元素，
with a couple of exceptions which I'll talk about later.
包括之后我们还会学到的其他 UI 控件.
You need to be making those calls on the main queue.
它们都必须要在主队列中进行操作.
In other words, you can't put those calls in a closure that
换句话说，它们不能再其他队列的闭包
you put on some other queue. Okay, it has to be on the main
中执行. 必须在主队列中执行》
queue, all right? Now conversely, all non-UI
记住了吗？相反，所有和 UI 控件
activity that's gonna take any amount of time or resources,
无关的操作，可能会耗时，或耗资源的操作，
probably wants to be off the main queue. So it never blocks
就不要放到主队列中. 千万不要阻塞
the main queue. We want the main queue reserved for
主队列. 我们应该尽可能的将主队列的资源
doing our UI stuff as much as possible. Okay, now this is
用来调度 UI 元素. 当然，希望 UI 控件能及时响应
not only cuz we want our main queue UI to be responsive,
只是其中一个原因，
okay, that's the main reason, but
也是最主要的原因，另外
also it serializes the activity on the main queue so
一个原因，是因为主队列是串行队列，所以
that our UI is presented in an orderly fashion. If,
UI 元素能按照我们给的顺序来执行. 如果，
if we allowed our UI to be on all these different queues, it
如果允许在不同的队列中操作 UI，实际上却是是
could, things would be drawing at all different rates and
可以的，但是绘制速度就会不同，从而出现
overlapping, it would be
重叠，预测不了
unpredictable as to what happened on screen. Okay, so
界面效果. 所以
we use the main queue as kind of a synchronization point
我们需要要利用主队列的同步性，
where everybody comes back to draw on the main queue,
保证所有的绘制都在主队列中进行，
all right? Now the main queue can only pull a closure or
明白了吗？主队列每次会出队一个闭包或
a function off of the main queue and
一个方法，
work on it when it's quiet. In other words,
在静默时，执行它. 换句话说，
it's not off doing something else, like drawing or
它一直都是执行状态，比如在绘制，或
something like, like that. Now the system is using the main
在执行和绘制差不多的任务. 主队列会一直在
queue behind the scenes all the time.
系统后台运行着.
For example, you know about draw req. Right.
比如，你知道绘制操作吧.
I told you draw req gets called by the system and
我之前说过，绘制是系统在调用，
it doesn't get called, you don't call it,
你并没有手动去调用，
you don't tell it to, you just set needs display.
并没有让系统去调，只是告诉系统它需要显示.
Well, you set needs display and
设置在主线程空闲的时候
as soon as the main queue gets quiet, it goes and runs some
进行显示，系统会运行或调用某些
function that causes that draw req to be called. So
方法来进行绘制. 这便是
you see how that works, okay? So that's what's going on in
绘制的工作原理. 这便是主队列
the main queue. What about other queues? Okay, so
在处理的东西. 那么其他队列呢？看
there's, I'm, in the next slide I'm gonna talk about
这里，下个话题便会讲讲
two different kinds of other queues that you can use to run
其他两种不同的队列，能用来处理
all your non-UI stuff. All right? So the first,
所有和 UI 无关的队列. 目前，
not gonna talk about this now, that'll be on the next slide.
我们暂时不谈这个，这是下个话题.
So on this slide I'm gonna talk a little bit about how we
这张幻灯片还有一点东西没讲完，关于如何
put something on a queue and the main way we do it is
将任务放到队列中，最常见的做法是
with this function right here called dispatch_async.
调用一个叫 dispatch_async 的方法.
Dispatch_async takes two arguments. One is the queue to
Dispatch_async 有两个参数. 一个是要加入的
put it on, like the main queue or one of these other queues,
队列，可以是主队列，或者其他队列，
and the second argument is the function to put on the queue,
第二个参数是，要加入队列的方法，
again, usually it's a closure. You see how I'm using trailing
当然，通常是闭包. 我这里简单写了一个
closure syntax right there? Okay. This is two arguments.
闭包的语法. 这有两个参数，
One argument. Two arguments. So this is the closure you're
一个参数. 两个参数. 这就是加入到队列中的
gonna put on there. What's cool about these closures,
闭包. 看起来很不错吧，
they take no arguments and then return no arguments.
闭包没有参数，也没有返回值.
So they're really easy to, to [LAUGH] put into your code.
所以，非常容易嵌到你的代码中（笑~
Okay? And you can put anything you want in here. Okay?
你可以将任何想执行的代码扔到里面.
But if this gonna do UI, you better not put it on anything
当然，最好是将 UI 操作扔进去，而不是别的操作，
but the main queue. All right, so how do you get the queue?
毕竟这是主线程. 所以，怎样获得一个队列呢？
How do you get this little queue argument?
怎样传入这个队列参数？
Well, for the main queue, you call this function,
对于主队列来说，可以通过调用
dispatch_get_main_queue. Now, you might ask,
dispatch_get_main_queue 来获得. 你或许会问，
why is all these underbars and why does this look like this?
为什么这么多下划线，为什么这个方法长这样？
This is basically a CAPI, okay, from iOS before Swift,
因为这是基于 CAPI 的，属于 iOS，而不是 Swift 的语法，
and so it comes into swift looking like a CAPI.
所以这使得 Swift 看起来像 CAPI 一样.
These are Swift, these are just Swift global functions.
在 Swift 中，这是个全局方法.
But the reason this is not object oriented, for
它不是面向对象的，因为
example is because this is a CAPI.
它是 CAPI.
This, this is called grand central dispatch actually,
实际上，它被称为 GCD（大中枢派发）
that's why they all start with dispatch,
所以这个方法以 dispatch 开头，
all this multithreading stuff, and that's why it looks like
这就是为什么，所有这类多线程接口，都和这个类似.
this. I'm gonna show you the object-oriented way to do
之后我会介绍怎么用面向对象的方式使用
this in a minute, but actually we're gonna end up using these
这些接口，在此之前，你还会继续
C-like ones more often, all right? So, again, all UI stuff
使用 C 语言的风格的接口. 再次强调，所有 UI 的操作
have to be on this main queue. It's a serial queue, okay, so
都必须在主队列中进行. 这是个串行队列，
nothing happens concurrently on this queue,
所以这个队列中不可能有并行的操作出现，
things happen in order in the order they go in, okay?
入队是什么顺序，出队就是什么顺序，有问题吗？
And, but all time-consuming stuff,
所有耗时的操作，
okay, or even worse stuff that might block,
或其他耗资源的操作，都可能造成阻塞，
like you're going out to the network to get an image,
就像网络请求图片这类的操作，
like we are doing where that block's waiting for
或者其他因等待网络响应，
the Web server on the other side to respond,
而导致阻塞的操作，
all that wants to happen off the main queue.
这些操作，都不应该出现在主队列中.
Now you still dispatch to that queue using dispatch_async.
目前我们在使用 dispatch_async 来派发队列.
You go down here and you say look at the bottom,
看到讲义的底部，
it says dispatc_async, not the main queue in here.
参数这里写到，不一定非要传入主队列.
And I'll talk about where you get that queue in a second.
之后会讲到如何获得其他队列.
And then open curly brace,
接着，代码包含在大括号中，
so this is a closure, inside that closure you do the non-UI
所以这是一个闭包，在闭包中，执行的是和 UI 无关的
thing that takes a long time or blocks. And then still
操作，它可能会花很长时间，或者发生阻塞. 接着又是一个
inside this closure, you dispatch_async again. This
闭包，再次 dispatch_async. 这次
time back to the main queue to do the UI stuff that you need,
回到了主队列中，处理和 UI 相关的操作，
maybe that the image you got from doing this, you now put
可能是你请求完了图片，需要
this in the UI here. So look how I'm dispatching within
扔到 UI 上进行显示. 所以来看看如何通过闭包
a closure. So can you imagine this outer closure
来派发它们. 你能想象外部闭包
is off running on some other thread in some other queue and
在其他队列的其他线程上运行，
in the middle of it, it puts a block of code,
然后在其中，又有一个代码块，
this block right here,
就是这个代码块，
this closure. It puts it back on the main queue, this one
这个闭包. 又回到了主队列，
continues to run after that in fact dispatc_async,
继续通过 dispatch_async 方法执行操作，
that function always returns immediately. Because all it
这个方法会立即返回. 因为它是将任务
does is put things on queues, it doesn't actually execute
扔到队列中，而没有真正执行
any of the code inside the block.
代码块中的代码.
It just puts that block of code onto the queue. Okay, and
只是将代码块扔到了队列中.
then this outer closure just happily runs to completion and
接着，这个外部闭包就
it's done. Meanwhile, that inner block has been posted
执行完了. 与此同时，内部闭包也扔到了
on the main queue and it's just waiting for
主队列中，等待
the main queue, for it to be first in line and
主队列执行. 排到主队列中，
for the main queue to be quiet, and
当主队列空闲下来，
then it'll pick it up and run it. You got it? So this is why
便会出队并执行. 这就是为什么
we use the C function notation because it reads really cool,
我们会用 C 函数，因为看起来真的挺酷的.
okay? Dispatch off the queue this, then dispatch the main
先派发这个队列，然后派发
queue this, okay? It reads very clearly to the person
主队列. 很容易让阅读代码的人
who's reading your code what you intend. Okay, but
明白你的意图. 但是
you do have to remember that this is async,
注意这些都是异步的，
it's out of sync. Just because you say to execute this code,
不是同步的. 因为我们并不需要显性调用这些代码，
it's not gonna happen right away.
这些代码不会立刻执行.
It's just being put on that queue, it'll happen sometime
只是将它们加入到队列中，它们会在
in the future when that queue is ready, okay? When it rises
队列空闲下来的时候自己执行. 当它们是队列
to the top of that queue and the main queue is quiet, okay?
的队首元素，并且主队列闲下来的时候，就会执行.
So how do we get these not the main queue queues?
那么，怎么获得除了主队列以外的队列呢？
Okay, that we want to run something else on.
比如我们想要执行其他的一些操作.
Well there's really two ways to do it.
这有两种方式可用.
The most common way is to use one of the concurrent queues
最常见的直接使用系统提供的
provided by the system, okay? Now these
并行队列. 这四种队列
queues provided by the system there's four of them, okay?
就是系统提供的.
They each have what's called a quality of service and
它们有着不同的优先级的服务，
the quality of service is really how
服务的优先级其实就是
much attention the system gives to them.
系统会给予多少的关注度.
You can think of it as their priority. High-priority queues
你可以顺着优先级来认识它们. 高优先级队列
get a high quality of service. They get serviced a lot, okay?
拥有最高优先级的服务. 它们能获得较多的服务.
But it's not purely that, but it's generally that. So
但也不是绝对的，只是大致上来说而已.
what are the four qualities of service here?
来看看这四种优先级的服务吧.
One is USER_INTERACTIVE. So, you can get a queue, you
一种是 USER_INTERACTIVE. 所以，你可以通过调用
can call this dispatch, get global queue right here. And
get_global_queue 方法来获得一个队列.
you can say give me the user interactive queue. Again, it's
然后给它 USER_INTERACTIVE 优先级. 这是个
a concurrent queue, so it's doing things concurrently,
并行队列，所以会并行处理操作，
it's not serial. And user interactive means
这就不像串行了. USER_INTERACTIVE 意味着
the user just asked to do something.
这是用户要求处理的事情.
It's gonna take a little bit of time,
可能会花一些时间，
so I don't want to do it on the main queue,
虽然我不想再主队列中进行处理，
but I need this done as soon as possible because the user
但是我仍然希望能进行执行，毕竟这是用户
is interacting with me right now, okay?
希望立马响应的操作.
So, this is very high priority, but
所以它拥有最高优先级，
lower priority than the main queue, okay? So, this might be
但这仍然要比主队列的优先级低. 这可能是
something where the user is dragging with their finger,
用户在拖拽手指时，
and you're having to calculate something to make the image
你需要同时计算一些数据并
that's pretty intensive, time wise, and so
立即给出反馈，这时就应该将任务扔到
you put it off on the thread. The user continues to drag,
这种队列中. 用户继续手指继续拖拽，
they're not seeing the result and
但是没有看到数据显示，
then the result comes back in and
等数据计算完成时，
then the user gets to see the result. So
用户才能看到数据. 所以，
the results a little bit behind their finger,
数据会比用户的手势慢一步，
because it takes so much time, but
因为计算会花一些时间，
at least as their finger tracks the main queue is still
但至少主线程一直在监听
listening to their finger, okay, and responding, okay?
手指的轨迹，并且响应还是有的，
So that's what USE_INTERACTIVE is for.
这就是 USER_INTERACTIVE 优先级.
USE_INITIATED means the user just asked me to do this, but
USE_INITIATED 意思是，用户让我处理这个，但是不需要在
it's not in the middle of an interactive event so, you can
用户交互的时候去处理，所以允许事件
take a little bit of time but get back to me right away,
等待一些事件，但一旦处理完一定要有反馈
cuz the user just asked for this, right now, okay?
因为这是用户要求处理的
So, that's lower priority, than an interactive thing.
所以，它的优先级要比交互事件低一等
UTILITY is something that usually runs in the background
UTILITY 一般用于在后台处理
for a long time, okay? Maybe it's fetching data.
一些耗时操作，比如获取数据什么的.
It's cleaning up some database somewhere. It's doing
也可以用于清理数据库，或者
something that the user didn't ask to do, but that needs to
处理一些程序必须要处理，
be done for this program. It's that kind of thing. And
而用户又没有要求处理的事件. 大致就是这一类事件.
then BACKGROUND is even lower priority. This is the kind of
BACKGROUND 的优先级最低. 一般将一些可
thing well it could run today or tomorrow. But you know,
今天，可明天处理的事件加到里面. 也就是，
it's really not something that I need done right away,
没必要立马处理，
I don't really care. So, it's kind of just a,
不需要过于关注的事件. 就好比是，
something that runs along in the background.
在后台默默执行的事件.
It's only gonna happen when things are really quiet,
在没有其他事件需要占用资源的时候，
when nobody wants any other service, okay? So, you get one
它才执行. 到此，你就已经学习了
of these four queues by saying dispatch_get_global_queue,
dispatch_get_global_queue 包含的四种优先级.
you specify which one you want. Then this has this
可根据需要选择. 除此之外，
extra argument ,0 which is reserved for future use, so
还有一个参数 0，这将在之后用到，
you just always put ,0 there.
现在就简单的传 0 就可以了.
And that's gonna give you back a queue, a dispatch_queue_t
这样函数就会返回 dispatch_queue_t 类型的队列，
that you can then use as your first argument to dispatch
它可以作为 dispatch_async 的第一个参数.
async, okay. So these are the, this is the cues,
那么，这就是，
these are the cues you're most often going to
这就是在你要处理后台事件时，
put this work that needs to be done in the background onto.
最为常用的队列了.
Now, its also possible for you to create your own
当然，你也可以创建自己的
serial queue. You call dispatch_queue_create.
串行队列. 通过调用 dispatch_queue_create 函数，
You give it a name. This can be any name you want, okay?
并给队列一个名字，任何名字都可以，
This is usually just so you can see it in the debugger,
这在调试的时候经常看到，
okay, this name is gonna appear in the debugger.
队列名称会出现在调试界面中.
And then you say DISPATC_QUEUE_SERIAL,
第二个参数是 DISPATC_QUEUE_SERIAL，
saying you want a serial queue.
表示你需要创建串行队列.
Now you will get a serial queue of your own.
这样就能获得一个自己的串行队列了.
And it's gonna be a pretty high priority queue,
这是一个优先级相当高的队列，
nothing like the main queue, but pretty high priority.
虽然不像主队列那么高，但也算是万人之上了.
Why would you ever want a serial queue?
什么时候需要创建串行队列呢？
Let's say you had a big table that you wanna download
假设你有一个长长的列表，想要下载
a thousand images to put in that table.
一千张图片扔到列表中
Small little images, okay? Well you could do it on
都是些小图标. 你可以
one of these user initiated queues or something like that.
在 USER_INITIATED 队列中或者其他队列中下载.
But it's gonna fork off a whole bunch of threads and
但是这样系统就会创建一大串线程，
try to download as many as it can concurrently.
而且尽可能多的进行并发下载.
Open a whole bunch of network connections.
同时发起一堆网络请求.
Whereas if you do is serially it will do it one by one,
但如果你在串行队列中处理，就会一个一个按秩序下载，
okay? So it kind of throttles, it's a throttling,
就像是限流的阀门，
a way of throttling your access to the network,
有限制的去访问网络.
all right? You usually don't need this.
不过通常不需要这个.
These are usually what you're gonna use for that not main
这些通常会在其他队列中处理，而不是主队列.
queue queue, okay? Now, we're only seeing the absolute
到此，你已学习了多线程必备的一些知识，
tip of the iceberg on multithreading here,
当然这只是冰山一角.
okay? There's a lot more to GCD, Grand Central Dispatch.
更多关于 GCD，Grand Central Dispatch 的内容，
You can look in the documentation for
可以查看文档，
all the functions that start with dispatch underbar and
所有方法都以 dispatch_ 开头，
you'll get an idea, there's at least a couple dozen in there.
至少有一打这样的方法.
I don't have time to cover it in this class.
我没办法在课堂上依次为大家介绍.
You won't need it,
其他方法你也不需要，
you won't need anything more than I just showed you for
除了我介绍给大家的这些方法外，你暂时还用不到别的
the work that you're gonna be doing in your assignments.
包括课后作业也不会用到.
In your final project, you probably also won't need
甚至是最终考核项目，你都可能用不上
anymore than that, but at least you know where to look,
别的方法，但至少要知道用的时候，
if you might need more. There is an object-oriented
能在哪里查到. 这是面向对象的
way of doing all this called, there's two classes,
调用方式，提供了两个类，
NSOperationQueue, which is kind of like dispatch queues.
NSOperationQueue，和 dispatch queue 很像.
And NSOperation, which is kinda like those closures,
还有 NSOperation，和闭包类似，
right, those little functions. Why would you ever want this?
包含要处理的事件. 为什么我们需要这个两个类呢？
These do have a little bit of extra functionality,
因为它们在 GCD 基础上，
that they wrap from GCD, things like, hey,
还提供了一些额外的功能，比如，
I have these two operations and
两个事件(operation)，
this one depends on this one finishing, okay. And so
一个要在另一个结束之后发起.
I'm gonna put them in a concurrent queue, but
把它们扔在并发队列中，
don't let this other one go until the first one finishes,
也能保证一个在另一个结束之后发起.
right. So dependencies, you can have dependencies and
这就是依赖，你能对事件添加依赖.
things like that. We're not gonna talk about that.
课堂上不讲，
You can look at the documentation if you want.
你可以在文档中看到.
You can do, I think almost everything here with GCD.
我们需要的处理，GCD 已经足够了.
This would be more if you actually are building
如果你是在创建一个
something where there's queue are doing queues and
有很多队列，而且
these operations are doing the actual calculation. Like as
operation 都在处理相关运算. 就像
your model is doing, you're doing some scientific app and
建模一样，做一个科学相关的 app，
it's actually doing all this complex calculation where
并且在处理一些非常复杂的计算，
things depend on each other and all that stuff.
每个计算都相互依赖.
And so it has a lot of queues and a lot of operations going.
这样，就需要很多队列和操作了.
You wouldn't use it as much for things like, I'm fetching
也就这个时候，你需要使用到依赖，如果只是
something from the network and I need to put it in the UI,
需要从网络上拉取数据，然后在 UI 上展示，
and I want that fetched to happen in another queue.
即使想要在其他队列中发起请求，
That kind of stuff you're just going to use the dispatch
dispatch_ 相关方法已经够用了.
underbar, okay. Now, in addition to dispatch underbar,
作为 dispatch_ 的补充，
you have to understand multithreading from
你还需要从 iOS 的 API 中
the perspective of how iOS's API uses it.
理解多线程该如何使用.
Because there are plenty of methods all throughout
因为关于异步线程的方法，
iOS that do what they do asynchronously, using threads.
实在是太多了.
Okay? And the way you see this in the API, is that one of
你在看 API 的时候，其中一个
the arguments to these methods is a block, is a closure,
参数是 block，一个闭包，
right? It's gonna be a closure you provide, and
闭包内容由你提供，
the documentation for that function will say your
文档的解释是，你的闭包
closure's executed off the main cue, asynchronously.
会异步的在主队中执行.
So what kind of methods are we talking about here that do
这就是能解决我们之前问题的方法.
that? Here's one that goes and fetches a URL. Okay,
可以用它来拉取网络数据.
from the internet. Downloads it from the internet. And
进行网络数据下载.
when it, and it does it asynchronously obviously.
它会在异步中处理.
You wouldn't wanna block the main queue waiting for
你也不想要它因为加载 url，而阻塞主队列吧.
this URL to load. And when it comes back,
在响应回来后，
it calls this closure right here, okay? Now
它救护调用这个闭包.
inside this closure, you might want to do some UI things.
在这个闭包中，你就可以做一些 UI 操作了.
Like maybe you downloaded an image and you wanna put it.
比如显示刚下载完成的图片.
But you can't put that code right inside here.
但是你不能直接将 UI 代码写在这，
Because this closure is executed on a different
因为这个闭包会在
thread and on a different queue than the main queue. So
另一个队列的线程中执行，而不是在主队列中执行. 所以
what you would have to do in here is the same thing
这里你还需要
you have to do with the dispatch_async,
像之前创建 dispatch_async 一样，
which is you have to wrap dispatc_async ge_mai_queue
用一个主队列的异步线程去包裹它.
around it, okay? So here's the method. This is an iOS method
就像这样写. 这是个 iOS 的
downloadTaskWithRequest. It takes this last argument,
downloadTaskWithRequest 方法. 最后一个参数，
which is a closure. And inside there you're gonna have to
是一个闭包. 在闭包中，
do this dispatch to the main queue. Because if you wanna do
你需要回到主队列. 因为你要处理
something to the UI, because this is not happening,
UI 相关操作，就不能直接写，
this closure will not be executed on the main queue.
这个闭包不会在主队列中执行.
Got it? So we will talk a little bit about, you're just
明白吗？所以建议大家
gonna run into occasional iOS APIs that take these closures,
可以查查 iOS API 中，异步操作时，
and they're asynchronous. And you just have to know that if
关于这个闭包的描述. 你需要知道，要处理任何
you wanna do anything in the UI, you're gonna have
与 UI 相关的操作，都必须要
to dispatch async back to the main queue. All right, so
先回到主队列. 行，接下来
let's do a demo of this where let's fix Cassini.
我们来完善 Cassini demo 中的问题.
Okay, let's make Cassini so that it's UI's always
优化一下 Cassini 的 UI，
responsive even while it's off downloading these things.
使之在有下载任务的时候，也能及时响应事件.
All right lets go over here.
那么从这里开始吧.
Okay, all this is gonna be, all this code that we're going
先处理这些，这些在 ImageViewController
to have to do is going to be in our ImageViewController.
中的代码.
We're going to make our ImageViewController, so
先要将 ImageViewController 改为
that it is asynchronous, right? That it can load things
异步处理，这样就能异步
asynchronously. Before I do that actually though,
加载数据. 在实际操作之前，
I wanna talk one other thing we should be doing here,
我还要讲到一件事，
probably, in ImageViewController.
需要在 ImageViewController 中注意的事.
Notice that if someone sets our model, we immediately go
注意这里有一段设置模型的代码，我们在里面
off and fetch it, okay? Now what if we never appeared on
获取数据. 但如果我们从未将它展示在
screen? Okay, what if this or something that's in a,
屏幕上呢？如果这是个，
gonna be in a navigation controller, it got created,
这是个 navigation controller 之类的，虽然创建了，
but no one ever clicked to cause it to happen on screen,
并且进行了模型设置，
but someone set our model.
但是从来没有经过点击事件展示到屏幕上.
Then this wouldn't happen in Cassini, this app, but imagine
虽然这问题不会出现在 Cassini 中，但是要小心在
an app where you've got this image MVC and some incentive.
其他 app 中重用这个 image 的 MVC 结构或逻辑的情况.
Really we really wouldn't want to do this
千万不要出现这种额外的资源消耗，
fetch cuz it could be very expensive as we've seen,
这种资源占用非常昂贵.
right? It goes on the network,
明白吗？这需要用到网络，
it's pulling down this thing if I'm paying for
要从网络上拉去数据，而如果我允许
cellular data, it's costing me money! Okay,
蜂窝数据，这会产生费用的！
to get that Cassini image, so I probably don't want to do
所以，除非是在显示到屏幕上时，
this fetch image unless I'm on screen. If I'm on screen,
我才会去获取 Cassini 的图片数据. 只有在屏幕上时，
I definitely want to do this. So here I'm going to say how
我才需要这样做. 那么，如何判断是否在
can I tell if I'm on screen? If my view, okay,
屏幕上呢？如果这个 view，
this is my MVC's view the top level, if it's window
即 MVC 结构中最顶层的 view，它的 window
is not nil. Okay, that's a pretty reliable way to tell,
不是 nil. 则说明视图在屏幕上，
sorry, that you are on screen, right? Because your view,
这种验证方式很靠谱. 因为你的 view，
your mvc's view will not be in a window unless it's on
你的 mvc view 不在屏幕上，才获取不到 window.
screen. Make sense? We haven't talked about window much.
明白吗？我们目前还没讲到太多 window 的知识.
It's that UI Window class I told you that you really never
它就是之前我告诉你们的，
use it, and you don't.
永远不要用，并且你们也没有用的那个 UIWindow 类.
You're not going to send any messages to it here. But
这里不需要调 window 的方法，
whether it's nil or
直接判断它是否是 nil，
not will tell you whether your view is on screen.
就能告诉你 view 是否在屏幕上.
Now what happens though if someone sets my image URL like
那么，现在如果有人在 prepareForSegue 或者
in a prepare for segue and then I do go on screen later?
视图展示在屏幕上时，设置了图片 URL，
Now I have to fetch that image, okay? Cuz now I
我就回去获取图片数据. 因为下一步肯定能
am going to go on screen. So how can I find out in my view
展示到屏幕上. 那么如何得知 view controller
controller lifecycle that now I'm gonna go on screen,
生命周期中，何时展示到屏幕上呢？
which method? Which method in my view controller lifecycle?
哪个方法？view controller 生命周期中的哪个方法？
Do you remember? It called. I'll put it down here
还记得吗？它叫做...
next to this viewDidLoad one. ViewWillAppear. Okay, so
和 viewDidLoad 写在一起吧. 叫做，viewWillAppear.
viewWillAppear is sent to you when you're about to appear on
在即将展示到屏幕上时，会调用 viewWillAppear 方法.
screen. Okay and we always do super.viewWillAppear in
对于 view controller 声明周期的方法，
all these view controller life cycles, all right. So,
我们通常会先调用父类的方法，super.viewWillAppear.
here I'm going to say if my image is nil,
在这里判断，如果 image 是 nil，
then I better go fetch it, okay? So, this is one
那么就获取它，这样处理
thing I've done to increase my performance a little bit. But
能提升一点点性能. 但是
it's still not going to stop things from blocking,
依然没能解决阻塞问题，
because as soon as viewWillAppear happens,
因为当 viewWillAppear 调用时，
and I'm just about to go on screen,
并且视图在屏幕上，
my whole app is going to freeze while I'm out fetching.
整个 app 都被阻塞了，需要去获取数据.
Those big huge images, right?
去获取一张很大的图片.
So I haven't really fixed the problem. I need multithreading
所以我们还没解决这个问题，我需要用到多线程.
for that. But I just wanted to show you to be a little bit
我将会演示如何小心翼翼的
careful about when you fire off an expensive operation.
开启这一昂贵操作的技能.
That's what viewWillAppare, Appear is for.
这也是 viewWillAppear 的作用.
That's really where you wanna fire off things like going
你需要在这里发起所有的操作，
out on the network and stuff, okay? All right, so now let's
例如网络请求什么的. 那么现在就
do our multi guiding and fix this. We're gonna do this here
遵循着多线程规则，来解决阻塞问题吧. 我们需要对
in fetchImage. We're gonna make it so that fetchImage
fetchImage 进行处理. 我们需要使 fetchImage
does the actual fetching in another thread. All right, so
真正的获取事件发生在另一个线程中.
how are we gonna do this? It's pretty simple actually.
那么怎么实现呢？其实很简单.
We're just going to take this code right here which blocks.
只需要将这段代码，这个 block，
This blocks the main queue while it goes out
这个 block 是在主线程进行
on the network, to forget the contents of this URL.
网络请求来获取 url 内容的.
And we're going to use the GCD to
我们使用 GCD 来
put it on a different thread, okay? So I'm just going to
将操作扔到不同的线程中. 所以，代码应该是，
say, dispatch, async, okay? Remember, dispatch async
dispatch_async，记得吗，dispatch_async
takes two arguments. A queue and a block here, a closure or
有两个参数，一个队列和一个 block，即一个闭包或
a function do that. So I'm going to put on one of those,
一个方法. 我准备将处理扔到
concurrent cues. And I'm gonna put it on the one where
并行队列中. 优先级是
the user initiated it but it's not interactive.
user initiated，而不是 interactive.
The user's not in the middle of dragging or something.
因为处理中，用户不会进行拖拽等交互.
They initiated it so it's pretty high priority and
initiated 的优先级已经很高了，
so I get that by saying dispatch_get_global_queue and
调用 dispatch_get_global_queue 来获得队列，
the one I want is
这个参数是
QOS_CLASS_USE_INITIATED. This one right here, okay?
QOS_CLASS_USE_INITIATED. 第一个参数搞定，
This flags is always zero, right? And now I have this
这个标识直接填 0. 接下来配置 block，
block here, so I'm gonna double-click on that.
双击代码提示，
It's really nice, by the way,
就自动补全了，另外，
you can double-click on these things to expand the block.
除了能双击展开 block 以外，
I'm gonna use the clay trailing,
我使用的的是尾闭包的形式，
closure syntax here. Okay for my block, this block, you'll
完善闭包语法. 这里就是我的 block 了，
notice it takes no arguments, returns no arguments.
你可以看到这个 block 没有参数，也没有返回值.
I'm just going to put all this blocking junk inside here,
然后将这一大段 block 代码，扔到尾闭包中.
okay. So this is going to fix my problem, okay.
这样就能解决我们的问题了.
Except that it probably gonna make my app go all strange
不过这样写可能会导致 app 出现以下莫名其妙的问题，
because I'm gonna be trying to do this inside
因为我在
a non-main queue. All right, cuz this queue, this block
非主队列做了这个操作. 因为这个 block
right here is gonna be put on this queue, and so I can't do
会在这个队列中执行，所以我们不能在 block 里面
this inside of here. Question? >> Can you explain
做这个操作. 什么问题？能讲一下
the trailing, the plot,
尾闭包吗？
the trailing plot where you added the parenthesis and
应该在哪添加括弧，它是怎样
what it does? >> Yeah, okay, so
执行的？行，好的，
this used to look like this. Okay, so this is normal.
闭包以前是长这样的，这是一个普通的闭包.
I'm calling this function right here, okay? Sorry,
我在调用这个方法时，哦，不好意思，
this function right here. Here is its first arguments,
这个方法. 这是第一个参数，
see that? Here its second argument, okay.
这是第二个参数.
If the sec, if the last argument of any function is
如果第二个参数，如果最后一个参数接收的是
a closure, then you can put it outside of the parenthesis.
闭包，那么就可以将其写在参数列表以外.
See this dispatch_async parentheses starts here? So
这个 dispatch_async 方法括号从这里开始，
I just took this parentheses off of here and
我只是将这里的反括弧，
I put it over here. Okay, so now this is the first
移到了这里. 所以，现在这里是函数的
argument to this function, inside these parenthesis. And
第一个参数，在参数列表的括号内.
here's the closure which is outside the parenthesis, okay.
而这个闭包，在括号外面.
You definitely wanna get used to that cuz we're almost
这种写法你一定会熟悉的，因为之后我们
always gonna do it that way. And when people design APIs
都会这样写. 当开发者在设计 API 的时候，
they almost always put the closure at the end so
他们尽量将闭包扔到最后，这样
people can do this. All right, so
使用者就可以用尾闭包了.
what am I gonna do about this,
所以我也这样去使用它.
okay? I need this to be back on the main queue. Well,
现在我需要回到主队列.
very simple here. I'm just going to dispatch it back to
非常简单，只需要将它派发回
the main queue. Now, another thing I'm gonna do here,
主队列即可. 除此之外，还有一件事需要处理，
while I'm kinda at it is, let's get this NSData right
先这样，先将这里获取的 NSData
here. I'm gonna assign that to a local variable
使用临时变量接受一下，
here called content of URL, okay? And then I'm gonna put,
叫 contentsOfURL，
so that's gonna be happening in my other queue.
这一部分是发生在另一个队列中的.
And then I'm gonna dispatch async back to the main queue,
然后，调用 dispatch_async 回到主队列，
which I get by dispatch_get_main_queue.
传入 dispatch_get_main_queue.
Okay, same exact thing here, okay, here's the block,
这个是一样的，这个 block，
I'm gonna do the same thing. Click trailing, close your
和之前一样. 改为尾闭包，
notation, and now I'm gonna put this inside here, okay.
然后将代码扔进去，
But now the image data is this thing that I got right there,
现在 imageData 应该是这个，我将它放在这，
so that's content of URL.
所以是 contentsOfURL.
Okay, now this happening on the main queue, all is well.
现在，这就在主队列中执行了，全部搞定.
This image=UIImage, the UI kit thing. This is a UI kit thing,
这个 image 是 UIImage，UIKit 中的那个. 这个 UIKit 元素，
by the way, no, not actually because of the UIImage.
准确的说不是严格是，因为它是 UIImage，
That is the one UI thing you can do on a different thread.
而 UIImage 可以在不同的线程中处理，
But it's because when we say image= down here,
这只是进行了图片下载，
it's gonna do something like imageview.image=new value.
因为我们之后要将 image 赋值给 imageView.image.
Okay, well that's the UI kit right there, so
而 UIImageView 是 UIKit 元素，所以
that has to be on the main thread. So that's why I have
必须要在主线程在中处理. 这才是我们要回到主线程的原因.
to do that. Now notice we still have an error here.
注意我们这里还在报错.
Anyone know what this error is? It's pointing right here.
有人知道这个错误原因吗？有人知道吗？
What do you think it wants there? No idea?
知道编译器想要我们怎么做吗？没人知道？
It wants self there, because this is a closure. Okay,
它想要加上 self，因为这是一个闭包，
this is inside a closure. And remember,
这段代码在闭包中，记住，
whenever we have a closure and we use a property on our
无论何时，在闭包中访问属性或成员变量，
object, we need to put self in there to make it
都需要使用 self 调用，
clear that we understand this is being captured and
以此指明变量值快照，
kept in the heap. So as long as this closure right here,
并将它存到堆中. 所以，无论是这个闭包，
which it's got this closure inside of it.
还是这个包含在闭包内的闭包，
As long as this is out there fetching,
只要是在函数作用域外了，
it's going to keep this view controller in the heap, okay?
都需要将 view controller 保存在堆上.
Now if we wanted to here, we could do the week self thing
如果我们要在这里使用，还需要用 weak 修饰 self，
and have week self question mark and that way if the image
防止在图片数据回来的时候，self 已经被释放，
came back and our MVC had been thrown out of the heap,
导致 MVC 抛出的堆内存异常.
it would be fine, we would just ignore it.
这样就能避免了，就能忽略掉异常了.
Okay, but I'm pressed for time so I'm not gonna do that but
因为时间原因，我就不演示了，
you could hopefully imagine doing that. Okay, so
不过你们应该能想象出来.
everyone see what we've done here?
每个人都能理解了吗？
So that's really all we need to do. One thing that it's
这就是我们需要的全部处理. 对了，
a little, now, I told you that multithreading, it's pretty
还有一小点，现在我讲解了多线程，
easy to read this code and understand what's going on.
非常简单，一看代码就能明白.
But you've got to think of the bigger picture of what's
但是你想想，如果是在用多线程
happening with multithreading here. For example,
加载一张很大的图片呢，会怎样. 比如，
what happens in Cassini if I click on the Cassini,
在点击 Cassini 按钮时，Cassini 会怎样，
which is a kind of a small image, and
这还是张小图，
then I change my mind and click on Earth.
如果我临时改变主意，点击了 Earch.
Okay, so Cassini, which is small, comes back, okay?
现在，Cassini 这张小图加载完成，
This code is gonna put Cassini on screen. But then the Earth
那么 Cassini 就会渲染在界面上，这时候，Earth
is gonna come back and this code's gonna put the Earth on
加载完了，Earth 就会覆盖在 Cassini 上，
top of it, okay? So I'm gonna get this flashing thing,
所以就会导致 Cassini 图片闪一下，
Cassini, Earth. Or worse, if I clicked Earth first and
接着显示 Earth. 更糟的是，如果我先点击的 Earth，
then clicked Cassini, it would show Cassini and
之后再点击 Cassini，万一先展示 Cassini，
then later Earth would come in and it would be showing Earth,
之后再展示 Earth，然后 Earth 就是最终渲染的图片，
even though I clicked on Cassini.
即使我最后点击的是 Cassini.
Okay, do you see the problem, is that I'm firing off these
能明白这个问题吗？我在不同的线程中，
network things in other threads.
发起的网络请求，
They're coming back at different times. So
他们的响应时间可能会不同.
really I want to,
所以，
If I'm gonna be a good programmer here,
如果我是一个优秀的开发者，
multithreaded, I need to check and
在多线程中，我需要检查响应的
make sure that the URL that I'm fetching,
URL，是否是我之前获取的那个，
that's this URL right here, is still equal to the image URL
即这个 URL，是否匹配这个 imageURL.
that I ask for. Okay, then I'll do this. If it's not,
如果匹配，才赋值. 如果不匹配，
then maybe I could print something like ignored data
那么就输出 ignore data，
returned from URL, and then we'll put the URL in here,
returned from URL，然后将 url 拼在后面.
okay? And that needs self here, of course, cuz that's
这里也需要加上 self，毕竟
inside this closure as well, all right? Everybody got that?
这也是在闭包中. 都懂了吗？
So let's go ahead and run, see if this works. So
那我们来运行下，看看效果.
what we should have now is a very responsive UI, okay,
所以，现在拿到的是一个丝滑的 UI，
all the time, no matter what we click on, so let's try it.
整个程序都是，无论是点击哪个按钮，试试，
Earth, Cassini, see I'm able to click on different things.
Earth，Cassini，看见了吗，都没有被阻塞.
I can still rotate, okay. Whoops, wrong way around. And,
还可以进行旋转. 噢喔...旋转方式错了.
the it's gonna pick whichever the last one that I asked for.
无论我最后请求的是哪个，
It's still fetching right here. It's gonna eventually,
都会获取到争取的图片. 最终，
hopefully, get one. And maybe it's even easier to see this,
都会获取到一张. 可能要等会才能请求完，
maybe. Let's stop this action, go look on our iPhone, cuz you
停止这个程序，重新跑在 iPhone 上看看，
can really see it happening on iPhone because when we click
因为这个过程在 iPhone 上更清晰，
on them, it actually segues and comes back.
它会有视图的转场效果.
So watch this. Are we running here?
来看看. 跑起来了吗？
Oops, no, we want iPhone.
哦，不对，我们需要的是 iPhone.
Okay, so we go back here. Now I click Cassini,
好了，回到这个界面，点击 Cassini，
it's loading it, but I can go back, okay.
程序正在加载，这时我点击返回，
While this is still loading, I can go back and
但其实加载还在继续，
change my mind because my UI is highly responsive,
我能临时改变主意，能点击返回，因为 UI 并未被阻塞，
even though it's loading those things in the background.
即使图片在后台加载.
When they eventually arrive, it's gonna put them in the UI,
当图片下载完成后，便会在 UI 上显示，
okay. But while they're out there fetching I can do things
但在下载过程中，
like go back in my navigation controller. Make sense,
我可以做其他的操作，比如点击返回按钮等。看吧，
see that? >> [INAUDIBLE]
没问题。[清不清楚]
>> What happens, what?
什么事？怎么？
>> [INAUDIBLE] Image each time
[听不清] 假设每次
you click out. >> So the question is, if I
都快速返回。那么，每次返回后，
click out, and then click back in, does it reload the image?
再点进去，会重新下载图片吗？
And the answer is absolutely, because when I click out,
答案显而易见，因为再返回后，
it throws that MVC out of the heap. Okay, it's gone.
MVC 的堆内存就被销毁了，也就不存在了。
Now actually, that MVC is not gonna immediately leave
但这次，MVC 却没有立即销毁，
the heap, cuz that closure that's doing the fetching is
因为闭包还在执行下载，
still holding it in the heap. But once that fetch comes
持有了该内存。当数据下载完成后，
back, then it'll leave the heap and the image with it. So
堆内存便销毁了，下载的图片也是。
yeah, every time we're re-fetching, okay?
所以，每次都是重新下载的，明白？
So see how we built this nice responsive UI right now, okay?
这就是我们讲到的快速响应 UI。
Everybody got that?
大家都明白吗？
Even though it's still taking a long time to fetch things,
即使数据下载依然需要很长时间，
we can still navigate. Now, what's a little weird about
但并不影响跳转。但是，UI 还有些
this UI, though, is that while it's fetching,
不足，在数据下载时，
like when I'm here, it's not clear what's going on.
比如这个界面，并不知道它在处理什么。
It looks like there's just no Earth image,
这里好像并没有 Earth 的图片，
I guess. I don't know, I guess not, I don't see it. Wouldn't
我也不知道，可能是吧，什么都看不见。如果
it be cool if we could give some feedback to the user?
能给用户一个标识不是更好吗？
Hey, I'm working on it, okay, this image is big.
Hey，我正在努力加载呢，图片太大了。
All right, and we can do that.
是的，我们可以处理。
And the cool way to do that is with a little spinner, okay,
可以在这里加个指示器，
a little animating. You see them all in apps little thing
一个小动画。在很多 app 中都能看到
that spins around basically telling him yeah, yeah,
指示器，告知系统收到了交互，
I know, I'm working on it. So let's put a spinner in there.
正在进行处理。那么，让我们在这里加上指示器吧。
Turns out to be really easy to put, do spinners in iOS.
在 iOS 中加指示器，真的非常简单。
We're just gonna go to the storyboard, okay.
打开 storyboard，
I'm gonna put the spinner here in this view. Now when I put
将指示器加到这个 view 中。但注意，
it in there, I'm gonna have to be very careful.
加进去要非常小心。
And this is a good chance for
正好给大家
me to show you more about the document outline. But
详细演示下 document outline。
watch this, so I'm gonna go down here. The spinner is just
看这里，滚到这里，有个可以直接
a thing you can drag out. You see it right here.
进行拖拽的指示器。就是这个。
Now watch what happens when I drag this out, okay, and
将它拖到界面中，
I try to use the blue lines to put it in the middle, drop it.
蓝色辅助线可帮助居中，就扔到这。
It looks like, okay, that worked, that's nice.
看起来不错，正是我们需要的。
I can even go here and inspect it up here.
还可以打开上面的 inspect，
You see, I can make a nice larger one. Maybe I'll even
这里，可以选择更大的样式。也可以
make it blue instead of white. Let's have it hide itself
将其改为蓝色。还可以设置
when it stops animating.
动画停止时，自动隐藏。
We can do all kinds of cool stuff here. But
这里可以设置很多属性。
actually something terrible has happened,
但同时引发了一个问题，
which is that when I dragged that thing out and
在我将控件拖出来，
dropped it in the middle there,
然后放置到中间时，
it made it a subview of the Scroll View, okay?
这个控件变成了 Scroll View 的子视图。
In the interface builder when you drag a view out on top of
在 interface builder 中，如果将一个控件拖到
another view, it makes it a subview of that.
另一个控件上，那该控件就成了另一个的子视图。
Now you can't really tell that here, but that's what this
直接从这里不大看的出来，
little guy over in the corner, the document outline,
要点击角落里的这个小按钮，打开 document outline，
is really great at. If you look at the document outline,
这非常棒，在 document outline 中，
do you see how the activity indicator is indented
能看到 activity indicator 在
from the Scroll View? Okay, that means it's a subview
Scroll View 中吗？这就意味着，它成为了
of the Scroll View. Now, if you don't want that, okay,
Scroll View 的子视图。如果你不想这样，
no problem. You can just drag it up above.
没问题，将它拖到上面。
Now, it's not a subview of the Scroll View. Now, of course,
现在，它就不再是 Scroll View 的子视图了。当然，
it's not in the right order right now, because I want this
这还不是正确的视图层级，因为我想要指示器
thing to be in front of the Scroll View. So, I'm gonna put
放在 Scroll View 前面。所以，要把
the Scroll View on top of it. So, now they're siblings, and
Scroll View 移到指示器上面。现在，它们就在一个层级了，并且
this one is in front, because remember, the subview is list,
这个再上面，记住，子视图是链表，
the top ones are in the back.
越在后面，层级越高。
The other ones go towards the front. So,
升序排列。所以，
now we have this thing in the front, okay? Now,
现在这个就在前面了。
another thing is, what if I wanna have,
还有个问题，如果我想，
constraints on this to keep this in the middle?
想要给该空间加约束，是它一直居中，该怎么办？
Well, I have to be very careful here too,
这一步同样需要仔细。
cuz those dashed lines. We're referring to the scroll view.
因为这里的约束，都是与 scroll view 关联的。
So if I tried to do reset to suggested constraints here,
所以，先要重置默认的约束，
I'm gonna get constraints that constrain the activity
会发现现在 activity indicator
indicator to the scroll view. I don't want that.
的约束都是基于 scroll view 的，我可不想这样。
I want the activity indicator to be in the middle of its
我希望 activity indicator 相对其父视图
superview.
居中。
And watch this, you can do control drag in the document
看仔细了。你可以在 document outline 中，
outline. So I'm gonna control drag from my activity
按住 control。从 activity indicator 这里，
indicator to its superview in the document outline,
按住 control，拖到 document outline 中的父视图上，
not over here, but in the document outline.
不是这，是在 document outline 中。
And when I let go, I can do things like, yeah,
松开鼠标，可以看到这个，是的，
please center it vertically and horizontally in yourself.
请在水平与竖直方向都居中。
Okay? So now this thing is centered and middle. Okay?
那么，现在就居中了。
So, now we've got the spinner, how do we do anything with it?
至此指示器就创建好了，那应该怎么处理逻辑呢？
Well, we need an outlet to it.
现在需要一个它的 outlet。
So, I'm going to bring out my code over here, okay?
把代码显示出来，
Do it automatic.
自动关联文件。
Got our image view controller here, let's give it to this,
这是 image view controller。关掉这个，
give it to that, give it some room. Okay so
关掉这个，腾点空间出来。好的，
I'm just going to create an outlet from this little
将指示器从这拖到这，
spinner right here, over here. See it make sure that it's
创建 outlet。注意这里的类型
type is activity indicator view not something else, and
是 activity indicator，而不是别的。
I'm just going to call it spinner,
名字就叫 spinner 吧，
I like spinner as my name. And it's just an outlet,
我喜欢 spinner 这个名字，这是个 outlet，
it's a normal outlet just like our scroll view or anything
非常普通的 outlet，和 scroll view 或其他 outlet
else is an outlet. Okay just like your display was in your
没区别。就像计算器能显示一样，
calculator there's nothing particularly special about it.
没什么特别的。
So now that we have this nice spinner right here,
现在，我们拿到了指示器变量，
we just need to turn it on and turn it off. So where are we
只需要控制它的开始与结束。那什么时候开始呢？
gonna turn it on? Well, I'm gonna turn it on right before
我觉得它应该在其他线程开始
I start doing something on that other thread, okay. So
处理事情的时候开始。
right here when I dispatch onto this other thread to go
就是这里，在将处理 NSData 的 block 派发到
do this NSData, which is gonna block, I'm just gonna say
其他线程的时候，让
spinner startAnimating. And I'm gonna be even trickier and
spinner startAnimating。我准备在这里增加点难度，
go spinner?.startAnimating just in case
改为 spinner?startAnimating，防止
I'm fetching my image like as a result of prepare for
在 prepare for segue 的时候
segue, okay, because there my outlets aren't set.
调用该方法获取图片，而这个时候，outlet 还未创建。
So even if my app spinner's not set,
这样的话，在 spinner 还没创建时，
I'll just do nothing. Now where do I wanna turn it off?
没有任何响应就行。那应该在何时停止呢？
Its actually two places that you can turn this off.
应该有两处地方需要停止。
One good place might be down here when your image gets set.
一处是在图片加载完成后。
Okay? Cuz if someone sets your image,
在图片加载完成后，
then you don't need to be spending anymore.
spinner 就没必要显示了。
By definition, you're showing the image.
理论上，这里图片都已经展示了。
So, it will make no sense to be spinning such a good place.
所以，spinner 已经完成使命了。
Got to be a little careful though here because,
另外一个地方需要特别小心，
what happens when we get in here, okay?
这里会出现什么情况呢，
And you get to the URL here, and
这里是获得 URL，
the image data wasn't able to be found, so
如果 URL 未找到图片数据，
you never call set image, so it's never going to stop.
图片就无法创建，那指示器就一直没停止。
So you probably want to put in else spinner stop animating
所以这里也需要加上 spinner 停止的代码。
here as well. Okay so this is gonna stop the spinner in
所以， spinner 就会在
the case where it went off to the Internet to get something,
无网络，或者未找到数据的情况下，
and it couldn't find it. Okay, eh,
停止。哦，
little tricky. Okay, so let's see how that works.
小失误。好，运行看看效果。
Alright, here we go, let's try Earth, there it is,
跑起来了，打开 Earth，对，没错，
it's spinning, and we can go back, let's try Cassini, it's
有指示器了，点击返回，打开 Cassini，也有
spinning. Now when Cassini appears it stops spinning, and
指示器。在 Cassini 加载完后，指示器停止，
so it hides because we had, we set this switch over here
并且自动消失，因为我们之前字 inspect 中，
on this one we inspected it called hides when stopped,
将它设置为停止就自动隐藏，
right. And so since it hides when stopped, it's not here
没问题。所以，在停止后，指示器
anymore okay. [INAUDIBLE] Saturn,
就不见了。[听不清] Saturn，
spins okay then we can rotate. Big image, taking a long time.
旋转屏幕。是个大图，需要更长的时间。
There it is, okay? So see how we turn this into an app, it's
完成，没问题。这就是在 app 中的运用，
really responsive and really nice and it's being as fast as
非常友好，非常漂亮，说多快有多快。
it can. It's getting those images as fast as it can,
图片现在说多快有多快，
but from the user standpoint, it's very responsive.
从用户的角度来说，也非常友好。
You really wanna go with that way.
大家以后也应该这样做。
Okay, so now I'm gonna show two unrelated to this, okay?
接下来，我将提到两个不相关的东西。
But did you've asked about in Piazza. One is notice that
大家对 Piazza 有以为吗。在运行的时候，
when we run this, let's run again, watch what happens.
重新运行下，看看出了什么问题。
When we run, we get an empty image view controller
在运行起来时，image view controller 是空的，
which really doesn't make any sense. What we'd
而这不应该出现才对。我们想要的是，
really want it to, when we first run and this is empty,
在第一次运行的时候，这是空的，
we want it to come up showing this view controller. So
而我们想要的是展示这个 controller。
this is like with your calculator,
这和之前的计算器项目类似，
you don't want it to come up showing empty graph.
我们不想展示空的界面。
You want it to come up showing the calculator because
空界面什么用都没有，应该展示
the empty graph is useless,
计算器界面才对。
it just forces them to do that back thing right here for
这个还必须要手动返回，而且
no good reason. Okay, so how do we do that, okay this is
还不知道为什么要这样。那么，该怎么处理呢，
another case where we need to use delegation.
这是另个需要用到 delegation 的原因。
In this case it's the split view delegate. Okay, split
这里要用到的是 split view delegate。split
view controller's delegate. So what does this code look like?
view controller 的 delegate。那代码该怎么写呢？
I'm gonna put this in Cassini, view controller right here.
我准备把代码放在 Cassiini view controller 的这个地方。
The first thing I need to do is I need to make the Cassini
首先，我准备，我准备将 Cassini view controller 设为
view controller be its own split view's delegate.
split view 的 delegate。
In other words, it needs to be the delegate of
也就是说，它需要成为
the split view it's in.
split view 的代理。
So I'm gonna do this in viewDidLoad. Okay sometimes
我准备在 viewDidLoad 里面处理。
viewDidLoad is not quite early enough to do things for
在 viewDidLoad 中，获取 split view 才
split views. We might have to do it in a wait for even. But
不算太早。别的方法可能还要判断时机，而
this will work in viewDidLoad. And I'm just going to set
viewDidLoad 就不用。我准备在这里设置
my split view controllers remember MVC knows the split
split view controller，每个 MVC 能拿到 split
view controller its in. Or the navigation controller its in,
view controller 变量。Navigation controller 也可以，
or the tab bar controller its in. So
tab bar controller 也行。
SplitViewController says what it is, might be nil, okay? But
而 splitViewController 也可能为空，
if it's not I'm gonna set its delegate to be myself.
如果不为空，则设置 self 为 delegate。
Of course as soon as I do this I'm getting an error because
当然，这样处理会出现错误，
I didn't say that I was a UI SplitViewController delegate.
因为 self 还未遵循 UISplitViewControllerDelegate。
So I need to go up here and
滚动到顶部，
say that I'm a UI SplitViewController delegate.
声明 self 遵循 UISplitViewControllerDelegate。
All right that satisfies that error. All is good. Now which
好的，错误解决了。没问题，那么，
split view controller method am I going to implement?
应该实现 split view controller 的哪个方法呢？
Okay hold on your chairs for this one, okay
抓紧椅子，别被吓到了。
by the way again on the split view controller delegate so
因为已经遵循 split view controller delegate，所以
I can just start typing split view and you can see it
键入 split view 就可以索引出方法，看吧，
shows me all the split view controller delegate methods.
这些，全都是 split view controller delegate 的方法。
There's quite a few. Okay about a dozen of them.
有很多方法，大概十多个。
And the one I want is the one that controls
而我需要的那个，
the collapsing of the detail on top of the master.
是可以控制 detail 压缩的方法。
Because I don't want it to collapse that detail on top of
因为在 detail 没有数据时，不需要将
the master if the detail is empty, okay?
detail 显示出来。
If it doesn't have an image in there,
如果没有图片，
I don't want it to do that. So this thing that controls that
就不需要显示。这个方法叫做，
it's called, called secondary view controller,
叫做 secondary view controller，
on to primary view controller. Okay, called
on to primary view controller。
secondary view controller, on to primary view controller.
secondary view controller，on to primary view controller。
Now, notice it returns a Bool, this Bool
注意，返回值为 Bool，如果
you return true if you took care of this.
返回 true，就是自行处理。
Return false if you want the system to do the collapse.
如果返回 false，表示交由系统处理。
Okay, so this is a way where the delegate can do this
collapse if it wants, or not, and
it just lets the split view know whether it did it or not.
So that's what the bool is, let it know when it did it.
So, this is actually quite simple right here.
We just want to get the image view controller,
okay? Well first of all let's make sure that the primary
view controller, content view controller, is ourself.
Now it should be, because we're setting ourselves
as our own split view delegate, so we should be
the primary view controllers, the masters content Okay?
So we showed you that, that should not be a problem. But
now I'm gonna say, on top of that, if I can let ivc =
the secondaryViewController, that's the detail.
It contentViewController as an ImageViewController. Okay? So,
if have a ImageViewController as my detail, and
where, everyone know about where, right? You did your
reading assignments, you know about where. Where is
an additional clause that you can add onto an if, okay?
So I'm gonna say where the image view controllers
image URL is nil. So if I have an image view controller as
my detail and it's, image url is nil, then it's empty.
There's nothing in there. There's no Saturn or
anything else. So in this case I'm going to return true,
which is me telling the system, yeah,
I took care of that. Okay, I put that detail, I collapsed
that detail on top of the master, don't worry about it.
Now I didn't, didn't actually do anything, that's good,
cuz that's what I want. I don't want that
detail to be collapsed on top of the master if the thing is
nil. All right, so I just kind of lied to the system and told
them I handled it when in fact I didn't. Okay, otherwise,
we're just gonna let the system do whatever it does,
okay. Return false, we did not handle this so you handle it.
Okay, so let's see if that works. Okay, so here it is,
look at that. It came up, didn't show me a blank thing,
so it worked. Now let's click on one of these. Woop, okay,
it worked. So
it collapsed the secondary on top of the primary when I
wanted it too, okay? But if it came up nil,
then it didn't show it. Everyone understand that? I
know it seems a little, a lot of long words in here [LAUGH]
like primary view controller, secondary view controller, but
this is just master in detail, that's all this is. And
we're just checking where the image URL's nil and just
returning that, we handled it when we really didn't handle
it because we don't want it handled. Okay. One other
thing I want to show you is reusing the detail in iPad.
Look at iPad. And we have the master detail right here.
Every time we click on this thing, it's creating a new MVC
here. Okay? Creating a brand new MVC. And if there,
there's really no reason for that. Okay?
We could absolutely just reuse this MVC right here.
Okay, we don't have to create a new one every time.
So, how would we do that? How would we reuse this?
Well, if we're gonna reuse this, we can't use
segues because segues always create a new MVC.
That's what segues do, they create a new MVC.
So, we can't use segues, okay, to do that in that case. So,
lets go back to our Cassini right here. Our, storyboard.
And we're not going to use these segues over here. Okay,
see these three segues? I'm gonna get rid of them.
Get rid of, oops, not that. Click here,
get rid of that one,
I'm gonna get rid of that one, I'm gonna get rid of that one.
Cuz I cannot segue from these buttons or
it will constantly create a new one of these details.
Instead, what I'm gonna do is to use target action.
So I'm just gonna bring up my code here, some space,
all right, and I'm gonna do a target action message from
each of these that reuses the detail to show the image.
So let's do that. Let's just go Ctrl+drag here.
I'm gonna call this show image, that's a good name for
this action right here, and I'm gonna have UI button
be the center, cuz I'm gonna know which one to show because
I'm gonna look at the sender. Okay. So,
I got show image right here. So, let's go ahead and
put the code here. So, show image is a lot like,
looks a lot like prepare for seg, segue. We can only do
this if we're in a split view. Right, we can only do the show
image thing here, this trick, if we are in a split view,
sorry, let me, just so we can see what's going on here.
All right. Okay, we can only do a split view so
I'm gonna first check to see that. I'm gonna say,
if I can let the ivc = splitViewControllers,
if I have one, view Controller,
controller[1]. We know that's the detail, right.
And actually I don't wanna use sub one
because if for some reason my split view controller
doesn't have a detail, then view controllers only have one
thing so I'm actually gonna use ViewController.last.
Okay, because last returns nil if there's no such thing.
Okay, and then I'm gonna grab the content view controller as
always and I'm gonna check to see if that's an image view
controller. So in other words,
if I can get my detail as an image view controller,
then I'm basically gonna do this right here,
in here, but here I don't have to say sender as UI button
because the sender is
a UI button so I can just say sender and
it's never gonna be nil there. Okay? And do that. So see,
see what's going on here? So no segueing,
I'm not doing any segueing. So when I go over here, Okay,
and I pick something, like Cassini, or Earth, okay,
we'll say. It loads it up. Actually,
we got to do one other thing, sorry. Back here, in our
storyboard, let's wire up all these buttons to do that.
[LAUGH] Okay, we only wired up earth to do this show image so
let's do that. Let's go to automatic.
All right, so let's control,
so this one here and let's wire up this one here. Okay,
so now all three buttons are sending that same show image.
So now we can actually demonstrate this. So let's
do Cassini. Here it is showing this and once this appears, or
even before it appeared, I could hit Earth and
it just reusing this. No seugues, so there's no way I'm
creating a new MVC here. It's just reloading it, okay,
just by setting the image URL on the image there. Got it?
Okay. Now, what about back on iPhone, though?
Let's go back to iPhone.
Is this going to work over here? No, it's not
because it only does that thing if it's in split view.
Remember I said if split view controller, so if I hit Earth,
it's not working at all now, cuz it's not segueing here. So
really what I need to do back here in Cassini is I need to
say [COUGH] if I'm in a split view controller, then do this.
Otherwise, I basically want to segue. Okay, so
now I'm gonna show you how to segue from code. Okay,
you've only learned how to segue from,
by dragging in Storyboard.
And now I'm gonna show you how to do it in code,
which is you just say performSegueWithIdentifier.
And you give it the identifier. So
we'll use the Storyboard ShowImageSegue,
and the sender can be whatever you want,
I'm gonna have the sender be this sender button right here,
this button that's asking us to show image, so
it's gonna be one of those Earth things or whatever.
Now this, perform segue with identifier,
requires that such a segue exist in the storyboard. Okay,
and we got rid of all those segues.
So that's not gonna work. We need to have a storyboard with
this identifier, and the way you do this is, you actually
segue from the view controller itself. Instead of seguing
from one of the buttons, when you wanna segue in code,
you segue from the view controller itself,
from this little icon right here down to wherever you want
to segue to. So we want to segue to this, right here,
put these close to each other. Okay, so I'm just gonna Ctrl +
drag from here to here. It's gonna be, it can be show,
because we're never doing this in a split view controller cuz
split view controller we're doing the other thing. So
we do show. We've got this thing here now, this one
segue, this segue sets up the whole view controller to here.
We still need to set its identifier to ShowImage. Okay?
And now, back here in this code, when we do perform segue
with identifier, it's going to do that segue. And
we're seguing from the view controller to the other one,
not with the buttons anymore, from the view controller, so
let's see if that works now on iPhone All right, Cassini.
Sure enough it's working. Okay, so
it's doing that segue, it's back to doing the segues.
So this is a new MVC. Go back. This is a new MVC.
But it's only doing it on iPhone because if you look at
our code over here in the showImage,
if it's in a split view controller, it just reuses
the image view controller that's already in the split,
in the detail. Okay? Got all that? All right,
I think I have time to do the last bit of slides here,
oops, which is on text field, go through it pretty quickly.
All right, so UITextField. I haven't been able to show
it to you right now because it requires delegation to work.
Without delegation, text fields don't work. So
UITextField is like UILabel but it's editable.
Users can touch on it and then a keyboard comes up and
they can start typing in it.
UITextField is not really a very main stream
input mechanism on the iPhone because the keyboard is very
small, okay? So, you only want to use UITextField when you
absolutely can't get the text from the user in any other
way. You can't offer them a choice
from a list of the things, they have to actually type it
in, okay? So, be careful, this is not a desktop app that you
are building. It's a mobile app. All right so,
TextField is not a primary input source. Now,
the keyboard appears whenever a TextField becomes
the first responder, and you can make a TextField the first
responder by sending it the message, becomeFirstResponder.
And then it will become the first responder.
You can make it stop being the first responder,
in which case the keyboard will go away, by saying,
resignFirstResponder, okay?
So, the keyboard appears and
disappears purely if there's something on the screen
that wants to be the first responder. Okay, simple as
that. Now, delegation is used here primarily with the return
key. So, if you bring up that little software keyboard
in the corner, there's a button called Return.
And if you click return the TextField's delegate will
be sent this message textFieldShouldReturn. It's
called ShouldReturn because it returns a Bool about whether
it should do target/action when that return happens.
Because a TextField is like a button, if someone types in
there and hits Return, it'll do target/action, okay?
You can control drag and
it'll target/action just like a button. But
this text field should return, either has to return true or
it has to not be implemented by the delegate for
that to work. But one thing, so usually do implement this,
because one thing you wanna do in here is resign first
responder. A lot of times when the user hits return,
you do the target/action, but
you want the keyboard to go away. So, a lot of times
you'll do that here and TextField should return. So,
you just need to set yourself as the UITextField delegate,
you've got to save it to the UITextField delegate, and
then you implement this method and inside just say sender,
which is the text field that's sending this to you,
design first responder. You can also find out when editing
has ended in your TextField, meaning that the user
clicked on another TextField usually and you've resigned
first responder. Okay, any time you resign first
responder you'll get sent this and you can ask the TextField,
ok, what text is in you. Okay, so that's another interesting
one. And as I said, TextField's UIControl,
you can do target/action, just control, drag.
The keyboard, you configure the keyboard actually by
talking to the TextField.
There's no UI keyboard object that you talk to in iOS, okay?
When you wanna configure your keyboard,
you talk to the thing that's bringing the keyboard up.
In this case, the TextField. And
there's all kinds of methods in here you could look at.
This is the UITextInputTraits protocol, so
that's where you wanna look in the documentation, for
this protocol. Remember,
a protocol is just a bunch of methods and bars, that's all
these are. And these will set what kind of keyboard it is,
you're entering a URL? Is it a password thing,
where you can't see the text? All that stuff Is part of that
protocol, so you wanna look that up. One thing about
the keyboard, it comes up over your UI so it might block.
It might even block the TextField that you're
editing in, if you're not careful about how you layer UI
out. And we are gonna talk later into the quarter about
this NSNotification center. It's a way to get notified
when things happened and when a keyboard comes up and
blocks your UI, you will get notified, okay?
And when we talk about this,
you'll understand what you can do. You could move your UI
up from out underneath it, or maybe it's in scroll view,
you could scroll up or something like that, but
you have to be careful about this. They keyboard,
just boom, comes up right on top of your UI and
it can really block things, okay? So,
you'll need to eventually learn how to respond to this
notification. There's lots of other TextField properties
that are interesting here. You can actually put a little
button on the side. You can decide where,
when the user touches it, does it clear out what's in there?
You can have a place holder in there, so
that when there's nothing in the field,
there's a kind of a light gray text.
Kind of telling the user what's supposed to be there,
that kind of thing.
Anytime I show you anything in this class,
like UITextField or UIButton or anything, of course I'm
expecting you to go read the documentation, okay. Otherwise
you're just not gonna know how to use these things.
I only have a minute or
two in these classes, in the lectures to
kind of tell you these exist. If you need to be able to go,
use the documentation to figure them out, okay?
And this is a classic example figuring out how to
use TextField here, Okay? Yeah, they have these left and
right overlays are kind of fun. You control the layout
all this all kinds of stuff. The keyboard has
an interesting bar in it which is sorry the input
trait protocol. Called input accessory view you can
actually put a little view on top of your keyboard.
You've probably seen that in some apps. Right,
has kind of like a little view has custom stuff,
you can put your own view just by setting this bar.
It's kinda fun. All right, so that's it. On Friday,
we do have a section. It's on UI Testing,
which is literally being able to record the UI being
interacted with and then writing code that tests,
to make sure it's doing what it's supposed to be doing.
That's really cool. A feature in x code. And then next week,
we're going to talk about Table View and
Core Data, okay?
Table View is a way of showing big huge amounts of data.
And Core Data is a database to store big huge amounts of
data in. Assignment four.
Since it's a table view based assignment,
we'll go out at the end of the next lecture, and it'll be due
a week later. And there are no more reading assignments.
I can tell some of you haven't done your reading assignment
because you don't know some of the questions I'm asking.
Go back and read that stuff, really.
it's not that much stuff, you should really understand all
these things, like the where clause,
or you're going to be writing weird code.
Because people say, why didn't they just use where there,
why did they put another if?.
Okay? So, you don't want to be that guy, okay? Al lright,
I'll see you guys next week. >> For
more, please visit us at Stanford.edu